<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Guangnan&#39;s Notes</title>
  
  <subtitle>I rest, I rust</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2020-03-31T00:23:48.479Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>ygnmax</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Refreshed Age of 23</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/29/PJ_02%20Refreshed%20Age%20of%2023/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/29/PJ_02 Refreshed Age of 23/</id>
    <published>2020-03-29T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-31T00:23:48.479Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have thought how I should summarize my age of 23 for a long time, because my experience is so diverse and colorful during this year that it is really difficult for me to abstract it in one word. But if I have to choose one, I will say it is a “refreshed” year, which is not only a summary from the hindsight, but also an expectation for the future.</p><p>After accepting the offer from the Master of Financial Engineering at NYU, I led a relatively relieved life. It had drove me almost 3 years, and to some extent, I partially achieved the dream from a very young age. But such is a human nature that we always want more. There was an inner voice telling me that I should do something so as not to waste the precious time: therefore, I applied for an economic research assistant and several internship at Beijing and Shanghai. Although they are quite different directions from the hindsight, I was thinking that if I went to the NYU program, I would prefer to continue pursuing a doctoral degree. Fortunately enough, I got the reply from the PhD candidate Franklin Qian first, and started to do the research assistant remotely. He has been patient and instructing me in hands for lots of tasks, and I am still assisting him for his papers now. </p><p>Here, I have to thank him for re-inspiring my academic passion and showing me a clear plan of pursuing academic career. The academic stuff, especially the empirical jobs, is really time consuming and I had spent a lot of time on the first stage of hand collecting. But after that, I had the access to more analyzing works, including building dataset by different tools, imputing a variable, setting up servers and et cetera. I used to consider myself as a meticulous guy when dealing with the arranging and analyzing tasks, whatever they are academic or industrial. However, after I did the research with him, I found there were much improvement I could make, from the thinking flow to the project management. The next stage is more about analysis work, I hope I can handle it and make more progress. </p><p>Considering that research tasks were remote, I started another plan to travel around the China, especially the southern China. There were several meeting held by NYU Tandon School in Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou in April and I needed to apply for the US visa in one of these cities. Coincidently, Derek Zhang, my undergraduate roommate, was working at Guangzhou and invited me to live with him. In total I traveled for almost 2 months. I went to Hangzhou, Changsha before I arrived at Guangzhou. During my stay with Derek Zhang, who was living in a serviced apartment in Zhujiang New Town, I also visited Shenzhen, Dongguan, Zhuhai, Macao and Hongkong. Actually, it was the happiest time I have ever had, not only playing with many old friends in XMU, DKU and high school, but trying a lot of new stuff for the first time: going to the hip-hop festival and concert well-known for rappers, riding around SongShan Lake, playing role detective game, watching football games of Evergrande Football Club, attending a seminar in other’s school, gambling and enjoy the fantastic atmosphere in Macao, enjoying the beauty before a social movement and experiencing the narrow dwelling in HongKong. I really appreciate that Derek Zhang shared his apartment with me which helped me save a lot of money.</p><p>Before I went back to Zhengzhou, I also stopped by Xiamen, Fuzhou and Shanghai to visit teachers and friends in XMU, as well as previous bosses I have cooperated with. Chatting with Arielle and her boyfriend (now her fiance), having dinner with Huan and lunch with Charlotte, I learned quite a lot from them. Because Derek persuaded me to have a travel in the U.K, after receiving the passport from the U.S. Embassy, I need go to Beijing for the U.K. visa. At Beijing, I lived with Endong’s apartment, near Wangjing, and met with the instructor of my education agency and old friends in DKU, XMU and high school.</p><p>Actually, during this period, I had spent a lot of time with my families. After I came back from Shanghai and before I went to Beijing, my father had to be in hospital and a surgery was necessary. Then during that week, our family members took turns to take care of him. Fortunately, he recovered and left the hospital soon. I also went back to Luoyang to celebrate my grandma’s birthday together with other relations. Basically, during the spring and early summer before I went aboard, I tried to say goodbye to most of my friends, instructors, families because I was aware that it is harder and harder for us to reunion again as time flies. I have to cherish these moments.</p><p>At the mid of July, I am on the journey of new exploration. My mother sent me to Xi’an Airport and I flied to London first, with transition at Helsinki, Finland. July, 23rd Qinhao Min picked me up at Heathrow airport and Derek Zhang joined us the next day. We went to the most famous places of interest in London, York, Edinburgh, Manchester City, Nottingham, Cambridge, Oxford. (I have uploaded our traveling photos on Instagram). I watched The Tempest performed by Shakespeare’s Rose Theater in York. it was the first time for me to enjoy Drama in English. I also watched the The Phantom of the Opera at Her Majesty’s Theater, which was really amazing.  I plan to arrange my travel notes in England and Scotland if I am free. I will update it in the future.</p><p>I spent 10 days in U.K. but I cannot say that I went abroad actually, because I was just with Haomin and Derek in U.K. We talked in Chinese and there was little cross-culture shock. However, as soon as I started to walk towards Security Check before on board, I realized that I had to face all the unknown situation all by myself. A little fear but more curiosity drove my body. When I sat down at the departure lounge, a sense of loneliness sprout in my heard, because there was no Chinese face, even little Asian face in my sight. But a black man and her wife sitting beside me warmed me a lot during the flight. It is my honor to meet and have a great chat with them.</p><p>On August 1st, I arrived at New York John F. Kennedy airport and started a new life. I met Shan Hui first and applied for cellphone number, Bank account, the Internet connection and the insurance. And most important thing is to settle down in the new apartment. (My roommates, besides Shan Hui, are Jiawei Wei, Yuxiao Cai.) The life in New York is colorful but expensive. It cost more than 6000 dollars each month for our 4 roommates in total. Moreover, it takes more than 1900 dollars for each credit in NYU. I should take the most advantage of the resource I can access, because the money is from my family.</p><p>The biggest challenge in NYU was the mathematics and quantitative stuff. The stochastic processes and stochastic calculus, coupled with Object Oriented Programming in C++ drove me crazy. But these were not the worst. I selected the class held by Peter Carr, the director of my department, on impulse. The outcome proved it was the terrible decision: I just collected all difficult subjects in the same semester. Although there are other excuses, to be brief, I ruined it. During the rest semesters, I have to try to my best to promote my grade point average. But every coin has two sides: I enriched myself in mathematics during the 4 months.</p><p>In the winter holiday, Tianhao Shen, Yifei Zhang and I traveled to Los Vegas and several places in California. Tianhao picked me up at New York and we drove to Boston to meet Yifei. Then we three flied to Los Vegas, with transition at Salt Lake City. We lived at Caesar and I went to casino again after 7 months. But this time, I didn’t gamble. even the slot machine. However, the steak in Gordon Ramsay’s restaurant and strip show excited me a lot. After having the most famous buffet all around the world, we flied to Los Angeles and started a road trip. Here, we had only one driver, Tianhao. Yifei and  I owed him a lot, even if we came across a small car accident during the ride from Los Angeles to San Francisco. We three spent the Christmas eve at Los Angeles and New year eve at San Francisco. I will never forget this amazing trip. </p><p>After coming back to New York, it was still in the winter holiday. It is the first time for me to spend Chinese traditional new year eve by myself, but I also met a lot of old and new friends during these time. NYC is where amazing happens, because you can also meet people out of your expectation. However, during the same time, corona-virus outbreak at Wuhan, and NYC would never forecast itself would be stuck by corona-virus and the most number of corona-virus cases all over the U.S. in 2 months. And on my birthday, it is just at the peak of corona-virus crisis. I have continuously stayed home for 2 months and only went out twice during the last 4 months. I hope NYC and everyone can be going well and survive it.</p><p>These days, a famous description about destiny, which is originally expressed in Chinese, always occurs to me:</p><blockquote><p>When you are old, looking back on your life, you will find that: when you decide to go abroad for study, when you start the first career, when you fall in love with someone, and when you get married, it is actually a really big change in the life. But standing at the intersection, you will never realize how complicated it is. On the day of making the decisions, in your diary, it was probably quite dull and ordinary. At that time, you thought it was an ordinary day in life.</p></blockquote><p>I cannot agree with it more when I was typing down these words, especially reviewing the last year. I realize and believe that the last year and the next several years means a lot to me. And this is where the word “refreshed” comes from: I wish I have the ability to keep myself refreshed —— whatever difficulties I will come across, however ridiculous thought I will have, whenever I am at rock bottom, I can always regain the strength and energy to move on. </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;I have thought how I should summarize my age of 23 for a long time, because my experience is so diverse and colorful during this year tha
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Thoughts" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Thoughts/"/>
    
      <category term="Personal Journals" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Thoughts/Personal-Journals/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Journal" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Journal/"/>
    
      <category term="Annual Letter" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Annual-Letter/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bash Basics</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/17/Bash%20basics/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/17/Bash basics/</id>
    <published>2020-03-17T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-18T20:17:48.007Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="List"><a href="#List" class="headerlink" title="List"></a>List</h1><h2 id="list"><a href="#list" class="headerlink" title="list"></a>list</h2><h3 id="1-options"><a href="#1-options" class="headerlink" title="1. options"></a>1. options</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment">## list the files in time order</span></span><br><span class="line">ls -alhtr</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -a: all files</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -d: show as a directory, don't show the sub-files</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -l: long information: permission, owner, sizes</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -l --full-time: full time </span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -l --full-time --time=atime/ctime/mtime</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -r: recursive</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -h: human-readable </span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -si: similar to -h</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -t: order by time</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -v: order by version</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># -F or -p: seperate the folders and files</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment">#### mtime: the latest revised time</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="2-filter"><a href="#2-filter" class="headerlink" title="2. filter"></a>2. filter</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">ls <span class="built_in">test</span>*</span><br><span class="line">ls D*</span><br><span class="line">ls -d */</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># filter to show the files</span></span><br><span class="line">ls -F |grep -v /</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># filter to show the directories</span></span><br><span class="line">ls -F |grep /$</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="3-order"><a href="#3-order" class="headerlink" title="3. order"></a>3. order</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">ls -lt</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="4-useful-link"><a href="#4-useful-link" class="headerlink" title="4. useful link:"></a>4. useful link:</h3><p><a href="https://www.cnblogs.com/sparkdev/p/7476005.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">linux ls命令</a></p><p><a href="https://www.cnblogs.com/peida/archive/2012/10/23/2734829.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ls命令</a></p><h1 id="Search"><a href="#Search" class="headerlink" title="Search"></a>Search</h1><h2 id="grep"><a href="#grep" class="headerlink" title="grep"></a>grep</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">ls | grep</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Check-files"><a href="#Check-files" class="headerlink" title="Check files"></a>Check files</h1><h2 id="Vim"><a href="#Vim" class="headerlink" title="Vim"></a>Vim</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">vim test.py</span><br><span class="line">vim ./test.py</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="head"><a href="#head" class="headerlink" title="head"></a>head</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">head test.py</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Process-Management"><a href="#Process-Management" class="headerlink" title="Process Management"></a>Process Management</h1><h2 id="top-htop"><a href="#top-htop" class="headerlink" title="top/htop"></a>top/htop</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">htop</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="ps"><a href="#ps" class="headerlink" title="ps"></a>ps</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">ps aux | grep ygnmax</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># ps = process status</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># a = show processes for all users</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># u = display the process's user/owner</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># x = also show processes not attached to a terminal</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Environment-Management"><a href="#Environment-Management" class="headerlink" title="Environment Management"></a>Environment Management</h1><h2 id="Modules"><a href="#Modules" class="headerlink" title="Modules"></a>Modules</h2><h3 id="1-install"><a href="#1-install" class="headerlink" title="1. install"></a>1. install</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># modules installation dir</span></span><br><span class="line">INSTALL_PATH=<span class="variable">$&#123;HOME&#125;</span>/opt/modules-4.2.1/</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">tar -xvf modules-4.2.1.tar</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># enter modules folder</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="built_in">cd</span> modules-4.2.1</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># install modules</span></span><br><span class="line">./configure --prefix=<span class="variable">$&#123;INSTALL_PATH&#125;</span></span><br><span class="line">make</span><br><span class="line">make install</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="2-usage"><a href="#2-usage" class="headerlink" title="2. usage"></a>2. usage</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># check the available software</span></span><br><span class="line">module avail</span><br><span class="line">module avail stata</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># load software</span></span><br><span class="line">module load statamp/15</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># list loaded software</span></span><br><span class="line">module list</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># unload software</span></span><br><span class="line">module unload statamp/15</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="3-useful-Link"><a href="#3-useful-Link" class="headerlink" title="3. useful Link"></a>3. useful Link</h3><p><a href="http://modules.sourceforge.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Environment Modules</a></p><p><a href="https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/50725572" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Environment Modules 简明教程</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;List&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#List&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;List&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;List&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#list&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;list&quot;&gt;&lt;/a
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Computer Science" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/"/>
    
      <category term="Tools" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/Tools/"/>
    
      <category term="Bash" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/Tools/Bash/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Bash" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Bash/"/>
    
      <category term="Linux" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Linux/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Conda Basics</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/17/Conda%20Install/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/17/Conda Install/</id>
    <published>2020-03-17T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-18T20:00:56.630Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Conda-commands"><a href="#Conda-commands" class="headerlink" title="Conda commands"></a>Conda commands</h1><h2 id="1-install"><a href="#1-install" class="headerlink" title="1. install"></a>1. install</h2><h2 id="2-Setting-up-Anaconda-Environments"><a href="#2-Setting-up-Anaconda-Environments" class="headerlink" title="2. Setting up Anaconda Environments"></a>2. Setting up Anaconda Environments</h2><h3 id="2-1-set-up"><a href="#2-1-set-up" class="headerlink" title="2.1 set up"></a>2.1 set up</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># list all available version in anaconda</span></span><br><span class="line">conda search <span class="string">"^python$"</span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># to create a new environment (the latest)</span></span><br><span class="line">conda create --name gy_env python=3</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># to create a specific version environment</span></span><br><span class="line">conda create --n gy_env36 python=3.6</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># activate the new environment</span></span><br><span class="line">conda activate gy_env</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># verify the version of Python</span></span><br><span class="line">python --version</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="2-2-activate-deactivate-update"><a href="#2-2-activate-deactivate-update" class="headerlink" title="2.2 activate / deactivate / update"></a>2.2 activate / deactivate / update</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># activate</span></span><br><span class="line">conda activate gy_env</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># or</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="built_in">source</span> activate gy_env</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># deactive</span></span><br><span class="line">conda deactivate gy_env</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># update the version (from 3.6.1 to 3.6.2)</span></span><br><span class="line">conda update python</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># environment information</span></span><br><span class="line">conda info --envs</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h3 id="2-3-install-packages"><a href="#2-3-install-packages" class="headerlink" title="2.3 install packages"></a>2.3 install packages</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># install</span></span><br><span class="line">conda install --name gy_env36 numpy</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># when creating:</span></span><br><span class="line">conda create --name gy_env python=3 numpy</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># remove</span></span><br><span class="line">conda remove --name gy_env36 --all</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="3-Update-Anaconda"><a href="#3-Update-Anaconda" class="headerlink" title="3. Update Anaconda"></a>3. Update Anaconda</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">conda update conda</span><br><span class="line">conda update -n base -c defaults conda</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">conda update anaconda</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="4-Uninstall-Anaconda"><a href="#4-Uninstall-Anaconda" class="headerlink" title="4. Uninstall Anaconda"></a>4. Uninstall Anaconda</h2><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># start with "anaconda-clean" to remove configuration files</span></span><br><span class="line">conda install anaconda-clean</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># then run the "anaconda-clean", this will create a backup folder called .anaconda_backup</span></span><br><span class="line">anaconda-clean</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># remove the entire diretory</span></span><br><span class="line">rm -rf ~/anaconda3</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># remove the PATH line</span></span><br><span class="line">vim ~/.bashrc</span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># Delete or comment out the following lines:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="built_in">export</span> PATH=<span class="string">"/home/ygnmax/anaconda3/bin:<span class="variable">$PATH</span>"</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Conda-commands&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Conda-commands&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Conda commands&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Conda commands&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-install&quot;&gt;&lt;a hre
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Computer Science" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/"/>
    
      <category term="Tools" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/Tools/"/>
    
      <category term="Conda" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/Tools/Conda/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Anaconda" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Anaconda/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Operational Risk</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/13/Financial%20Risk%20Management%20Operational%20Risk/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/13/Financial Risk Management Operational Risk/</id>
    <published>2020-03-13T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-13T17:35:45.505Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Operational-Risk"><a href="#Operational-Risk" class="headerlink" title="Operational Risk"></a>Operational Risk</h1><h2 id="What-is-Operational-Risk"><a href="#What-is-Operational-Risk" class="headerlink" title="What is Operational Risk"></a>What is Operational Risk</h2><p>The operations of a bank or financial institution refers to <strong>the mechanism by which these firms put their strategies into practice</strong> by employing professionals, developing processes, defining best practices and establishing the proper infrastructure (increasingly through the use of emerging technology to achieve strategic objectives.</p><p>Managing operational risk is a function of <strong>both internal and external processes</strong> related to cash and securities and managing client accounts and information. The approach must evolve along with changes in technology, markets and regulation.</p><p>More traditional monitoring in the form of periodic credit reviews and operational risks associated with transactional banking such as the segregation or safekeeping of client assets or data protection issues are critical risk monitoring functions</p><h3 id="People"><a href="#People" class="headerlink" title="People"></a>People</h3><ul><li><strong>Key person risk</strong> refers to any institution which relies heavily on one individual,<br>whether that be within senior management or operations</li><li><strong>Rogue employee or trader risk</strong> will always remain a concern despite of enhanced and automated methods of managing monitoring employee activity</li></ul><h3 id="Processes"><a href="#Processes" class="headerlink" title="Processes"></a>Processes</h3><ul><li>Procedural breakdowns in processing and managing market and credit risk as well as meeting compliance and regulatory requirements can create competitive disadvantages or result in opportunity cost and/or actual losses</li><li>It is important to continually review controls and incentives in place, and adapt to a changing market and regulatory environment</li></ul><h3 id="Systems"><a href="#Systems" class="headerlink" title="Systems"></a>Systems</h3><ul><li><strong>Errors</strong> resulting from outdated systems, lack of systems integration and/or gaps<br>where human intervention is needed can raise costs and lower efficiency</li><li>Increasing use of technology, in particular artificial intelligence, robotics process<br>automation and machine learning techniques to eliminate manual, error prone repetitive processes among banks and financial institutions</li></ul><h2 id="Where-is-Operational-risk-from"><a href="#Where-is-Operational-risk-from" class="headerlink" title="Where is Operational risk from"></a>Where is Operational risk from</h2><h3 id="Market-Infrastructure"><a href="#Market-Infrastructure" class="headerlink" title="Market Infrastructure"></a>Market Infrastructure</h3><ul><li>Central Securities Depositories (Euroclear, Clearstream)</li><li>Global Payments Network (Fedwire, CHIPS, etc.)</li><li>Exchanges and Clearinghouses (NYSE, NASDAQ, CME, LCH, etc.)</li><li>Securities Financing Transactions (Repo)</li><li>Role of a Global Custodian in Managing Operational Risk</li></ul><h3 id="Internal-Operational-Risk-Management"><a href="#Internal-Operational-Risk-Management" class="headerlink" title="Internal Operational Risk Management"></a>Internal Operational Risk Management</h3><ul><li>Identification</li><li>Assessment</li><li>Measurement</li><li>Control and Mitigation</li><li>Monitoring and Reporting</li></ul><h3 id="CSD"><a href="#CSD" class="headerlink" title="CSD"></a>CSD</h3><p><strong>Shift from Decentralized Physical to Centralized Dematerialized Processing:</strong> Until the Paperwork Crisis of 1968 NYSE stock certificates were physically delivered until brokers were overwhelmed by high trade volumes Firms failed and the number of failed trades (if delivery did not occur within five days) soared The NYSE established the Central Certificate Service ( to transfer securities electronically, eliminate physical handling, and track shares held by NYSE members</p><p><strong>Central Securities Depositories</strong> are entities which record legal entitlements to<br>dematerialized securities and operate transaction settlement systems in those securities Major CSDs, include DTCC, Euroclear and Clearstream</p><ul><li><p><strong>DTCC (Depository Trust Clearing Corporation, formerly CCS)</strong> DTCC is owned and directed by its users It automates, standardizes, and streamlines capital markets transactions</p><ul><li>DTC (Depository Trust Corporation) provides clearance, settlement, and information services for equities, corporate and municipal bonds, unit investment trusts, government and mortgage backed securities, money market instruments, and over the counter derivatives</li><li>NSCC (National Securities Clearing Corporation) executes multilateral netting to manage transactions between mutual funds and insurance carriers and their respective investors</li><li>FICC (Fixed Income Clearing Corporation) provides clearing for fixed income securities, including Treasury securities and mortgage backed securities, including real time trade matching, clearing, risk management, and netting for trades in US government debt issues, including repurchase agreements or repos</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Euroclear</strong></p></li><li><strong>Clearstream</strong></li></ul><h3 id="Payment-Networks"><a href="#Payment-Networks" class="headerlink" title="Payment Networks"></a>Payment Networks</h3><p><strong>SWIFT (Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication)</strong> is a cooperative utility messaging system formed in 1973 by over 200 banks headquartered in Belgium. In 1977 it replaced Telex technology with a messaging platform to validate and route standardized messages. Over 11 000 financial institutions in more than 200 countries now use SWIFT. As a secure financial messaging system, SWIFT does not perform funds transfer, clearing or settlement. SWIFT payment orders must be settled by correspondent accounts that institutions have with one other.</p><p><strong>Fedwire</strong> is a real time gross settlement funds transfer system operated by U S Federal Reserve Banks enabling financial institutions to electronically transfer funds between over 9 000 participants.</p><p><strong>Correspondent Banking</strong> Bilateral arrangement, often involving a reciprocal cross border relationship in multiple currencies. A correspondent banking arrangement involves one bank (the correspondent) providing accounts and related services, to another bank (the respondent), often including its affiliates.</p><h3 id="Exchanges-and-Clearinghouses"><a href="#Exchanges-and-Clearinghouses" class="headerlink" title="Exchanges and Clearinghouses"></a>Exchanges and Clearinghouses</h3><p><strong>Securities and derivatives exchanges</strong> provide a centralized location where securities are listed and traded by a restricted set of brokers who are members of an exchange; recordkeeping is dematerialized and based upon electronic communication networks.</p><p><strong>Alternative trading venues</strong> and systems including dark pools offer private means to conduct securities transactions These venues have faced increased scrutiny and disclosure (under Regulation ATS) given concerns over conflict of interest and other practices<br><strong>Central clearinghouses</strong> (CCPs) are centralized entities including CME and LCH which mutualize counterparty credit risk in the foreign exchange, interest rate, equity, credit, commodity and weather derivative markets in which they operate CCPs aim to reduce settlement risk via several measures</p><ul><li>Net offsetting trades between multiple counterparties</li><li>Require collateral (margin) deposits</li><li>Provide independent valuation of trades and collateral</li><li>Monitor creditworthiness of member firms, and</li><li>Provide a guarantee fund used to cover losses exceeding a defaulting member’s collateral </li></ul><p><strong>Advantages of central counterparty clearing arrangements</strong> are greater risk transparency, lower processing costs, and clear rules in cases of member default Once a trade has been executed by two counterparties, they are novated to a clearinghouse which steps between trader clearing firms to assumes legal counterparty risk for the trade (a trade between members A and B become two trades A CCP and CCP B)</p><p><strong>Disadvantages</strong> of central clearing include the concentration of risk which was previously decentralized and distributed in the bilateral OTC model, the interdependency of CCPs, which are now have become crucial financial infrastructures following post crisis reform which forced the over the counter derivatives market into central clearing and the limited capital held by CCPs themselves</p><h3 id="Securities-Financing-Transactions-Repo"><a href="#Securities-Financing-Transactions-Repo" class="headerlink" title="Securities Financing Transactions (Repo)"></a>Securities Financing Transactions (Repo)</h3><h3 id="Global-Custodian"><a href="#Global-Custodian" class="headerlink" title="Global Custodian"></a>Global Custodian</h3><p><strong>Global custody and fund services</strong> providers offer a range of financial services associated with the safekeeping of financial assets including the following:</p><ul><li>Hold in safekeeping securities such as domestic and foreign stocks, bonds, commodities and cash</li><li>Facilitate settlement of purchases/sales and deliveries in/out of securities and currency</li><li>Support asset income collection (regular and special dividends, bond coupons, maturities) and administer related tax withholding documents and foreign tax reclamation</li><li>Provide corporate action services on securities held such as proxy voting, stock dividends, stock splits, business combinations ( tender offers, bond calls, etc</li><li>Offer securities lending services</li><li>Maintain currency cash bank accounts manage cash and perform foreign exchange transactions</li><li>Perform accounting services such as NAV reporting for mutual funds, accounting services and complex sub accounting services for pension funds</li></ul><p><strong>Operational challenges</strong> outsourced by investors to custodians include the following:</p><ul><li><strong>Active subcustodian management</strong>: Custodians contract with local banks as agents, performing initial and ongoing due diligence on financial strength, custody expertise and capacity, technology, management and infrastructure, ties with local market entities, income and corporate action capabilities, internal/external audit results, contingency plans, insurance coverage and tax expertise</li><li><strong>Assist in new market expansion Clients considering expansion</strong> to a new market tap custody bank expertise on market structure, requirements and regulation When a custodian opens a new market to clients, network market managers work with local market representatives to understand the market and advocate for infrastructure changes to make markets more acceptable to foreign investors</li><li><strong>Asset segregation and ringfencing</strong>: Custodians conduct periodic legal reviews of recoverability of securities held on behalf of clients in the event of the bankruptcy of the subcustodian, maintaining omnibus and segregated cash and securities accounts in the name of the bank separate from subcustodian assets where possible</li></ul><h2 id="Manage-Operational-Risk"><a href="#Manage-Operational-Risk" class="headerlink" title="Manage Operational Risk"></a>Manage Operational Risk</h2><h3 id="Five-steps"><a href="#Five-steps" class="headerlink" title="Five steps"></a>Five steps</h3><p><strong>Identification</strong></p><p><strong>Assessment</strong></p><p><strong>Measurement</strong></p><p><strong>Control and Mitigation</strong></p><p><strong>Monitoring and Reporting</strong></p><p><strong>Compliance risk</strong>: Failure to comply with legal or regulatory obligations, codes of conduct and standards of self regulatory organizations applicable to the business activities of the Firm</p><ul><li><p>use the outer communication system (like whatsapp)</p></li><li><p>send restricted data from work desktop to an external domain</p></li></ul><p><strong>Conduct risk</strong>: Risk that an action (or inaction) by an employee or employees could lead to unfair client or customer outcomes, impact the integrity of the markets in which the Firm operates, or compromise the Firm’s reputation.</p><p><strong>Legal risk</strong>: Loss primarily caused by actual or alleged failure to meet legal obligations that arise from the rule of law in jurisdictions in which the Firm operates, agreements with clients and customers, and products and services offered by the Firm.</p><p><strong>Estimations and Model Risk:</strong> Potential for adverse consequences from decisions based on incorrect or misused estimation outputs</p><p><strong>Cybersecurity risk</strong> The Firm devotes significant resources to protecting and continuing to improve the security of the Firm’s computer systems, software, networks and other technology assets<br><strong>Business and technology resiliency risk</strong>: Business disruptions can occur due to forces beyond the Firm’s control such as severe weather, power or telecommunications loss, flooding, transit strikes, terrorist threats or infectious disease The safety of employees and customers is the highest priority. The Firm’s global resiliency program is intended to enable the recovery of critical business functions and supporting assets ( technology and facilities) in the event of a business interruption </p><p><strong>Payment fraud risk</strong>: Payment fraud risk is the risk of external and internal parties unlawfully obtaining personal monetary benefit through misdirected or otherwise improper payment.</p><p><strong>Third party outsourcing risk</strong>: To identify and manage the operational risk inherent in outsourcing.</p><h2 id="Quantifying-Operating-Risk"><a href="#Quantifying-Operating-Risk" class="headerlink" title="Quantifying Operating Risk"></a>Quantifying Operating Risk</h2><p>Expected versus Unexpected Loss</p><p><strong>Basic Indicator Approach</strong></p><p>Simplest form for banks without significant international operations Banks using the BIA must hold capital for operational risk equal to the average over the previous three years of a fixed percentage α of positive annual gross income (excluding year where annual gross income is negative or zero):</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">K_{BIA}=\frac{\sum GI_{1,2,\cdots,n}*\alpha}{n}</script><p><strong>Standard Approach</strong></p><p>This methodology used for internationally active institutions divides bank activities into corporate finance, sales trading, retail, commercial banking, payment settlement, agency services, asset management, and retail brokerage Gross income serves as a proxy for the scale of the business and operational risk exposure for each segment Capital charges are calculated by multiplying gross income by a β factor which defines the relationship between industry wide operational risk loss experience and gross income</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">K_{\text{TSA}}=\frac{\sum_{\text{years}1-3}\max(\sum_{i=1}^{8}GI_{i}*\beta_i)}{3}</script><p>Standardized Approach Beta Factors The beta factors are a fixed percentage, set by the Committee, relating the level of required capital to the level of the gross income for each of the eight business lines as follows:</p><div class="table-container"><table><thead><tr><th>Business Line</th><th>Beta Factor</th><th>NI Average</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Corporate Finance (β1)</td><td>18%</td><td>20</td></tr><tr><td>Sales &amp; Trading (β2)</td><td>18%</td><td>0</td></tr><tr><td>Retail Banking (β3)</td><td>12%</td><td>20</td></tr><tr><td>Commercial Banking (β4)</td><td>15%</td><td>25</td></tr><tr><td>Payment &amp; Settlement (β5)</td><td>18%</td><td>15</td></tr><tr><td>Agency Services (β6)</td><td>15%</td><td>10</td></tr><tr><td>Asset Management (β7)</td><td>12%</td><td>25</td></tr><tr><td>Retail Brokerage (β8)</td><td>12%</td><td>15</td></tr></tbody></table></div><p>Example:</p><p>Under BIA, $\alpha = 15\%$</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">K_{BIA}=130*15\% = 19.5</script><p>Under SA</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">K_{KSA}=\frac{\sum_{\text{years}1-3}\max(\sum_{i=1}^{8}GI_{i}*\beta_i)}{3} = 18.75</script><p><strong>Advanced Management Approach (AMA)</strong></p><h2 id="Operational-Risk-Mitigation-and-Control"><a href="#Operational-Risk-Mitigation-and-Control" class="headerlink" title="Operational Risk Mitigation and Control"></a>Operational Risk Mitigation and Control</h2><p><strong>Appetite</strong></p><p><strong>Existing Business</strong></p><p><strong>New Business</strong></p><p><strong>Build or Buy and Third-Party Risks</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Operational-Risk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Operational-Risk&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Operational Risk&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Operational Risk&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;What-is-O
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Economics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/"/>
    
      <category term="Finance" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/"/>
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/Risk-Management/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Risk-Management/"/>
    
      <category term="NYU" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/NYU/"/>
    
      <category term="FRM" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/FRM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Parameter Estimation</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/12/Statistics%20Parameter%20Estimation/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/12/Statistics Parameter Estimation/</id>
    <published>2020-03-12T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-13T04:05:24.392Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Estimator"><a href="#Estimator" class="headerlink" title="Estimator"></a>Estimator</h1><h2 id="Criterion"><a href="#Criterion" class="headerlink" title="Criterion"></a>Criterion</h2><h3 id="unbiased"><a href="#unbiased" class="headerlink" title="unbiased"></a>unbiased</h3><p> For $\hat{\theta}$ which is the estimation of $\theta$, </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">E_{\theta}(\hat{\theta})=\theta</script><h3 id="effectiveness"><a href="#effectiveness" class="headerlink" title="effectiveness"></a>effectiveness</h3><p>Assume $\hat{\theta_1}$ and $\hat{\theta_2}$ are both unbiased estimation, for $\forall \theta \in \Theta$,</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">D(\hat{\theta_1}) \leq D(\hat{\theta_2})</script><p>then $\hat{\theta_1}$ is more effective than $\hat{\theta_2}$.</p><h3 id="Consistency"><a href="#Consistency" class="headerlink" title="Consistency"></a>Consistency</h3><p>For $\hat{\theta},$ $\forall ~ \theta \in \Theta$</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\lim\limits_{n \to \infty}P\{|\hat{\theta}-\theta|<\epsilon\}=1</script><h2 id="Moment-Estimation"><a href="#Moment-Estimation" class="headerlink" title="Moment Estimation"></a>Moment Estimation</h2><p>$ A_k = \frac{1}{n}\sum\limits_{i=1}^{n}X_i^k$ is convergent to $\mu_k$ by probability, where $\mu_k$ is k-order moment.</p><p>If there are $k$ parameters ($\theta_1, \theta_2,\cdots,\theta_k$), then we could compute $k$ order moment estimation:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{cases}\mu_1 &=& \mu_1(\theta_1, \theta_2,\cdots,\theta_k) \\\mu_2 &=& \mu_2(\theta_1, \theta_2,\cdots,\theta_k) \\&\vdots& \\\mu_2 &=& \mu_2(\theta_1, \theta_2,\cdots,\theta_k) \\\end{cases}</script><h2 id="Maximum-Likelihood-Estimation"><a href="#Maximum-Likelihood-Estimation" class="headerlink" title="Maximum Likelihood Estimation"></a>Maximum Likelihood Estimation</h2><h3 id="Likelihood-Function"><a href="#Likelihood-Function" class="headerlink" title="Likelihood Function"></a>Likelihood Function</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">L(\theta)=L(x_1, x_2, \cdots, x_n;\theta)=\prod\limits_{i=1}^{n}p(x_i;\theta), \theta\in \Theta</script><h3 id="Log-Likelihood-Function"><a href="#Log-Likelihood-Function" class="headerlink" title="Log Likelihood Function"></a>Log Likelihood Function</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\ln L(\theta) =\ln\prod\limits_{i=1}^{n}p(x_i;\theta) = \sum_{i=1}^{n} \ln p(x_i;\theta), \theta\in \Theta</script><p>Example:</p><p>Assume $X\sim N(\mu,\sigma^2)$, $x_1, x_2, \cdots, x_n$ are samples, $\mu$ and $\sigma$ are unknown.</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}L(\mu, \sigma^2) &=& \prod_{i=1}^{n}\frac{1}{\sqrt{2\pi} \sigma}e^{-\frac{(x_i-\mu)^2}{2\sigma^2}} \\&=& \frac{1}{(\sqrt{2\pi} \sigma)^n}e^{-\frac{1}{2\sigma^2}\sum\limits_{i=1}^{n}(x_i-\mu)^2} \\\ln L(\mu, \sigma^2) &=& -\frac{n}{2} \ln(2\pi)-\frac{n}{2} \ln\sigma^2-\frac{1}{2\sigma^2}\sum\limits_{i=1}^{n}(x_i-\mu)^2\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>Compute the partial derivatives:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\frac{\part}{\part\mu}\ln L &=& \frac{1}{\sigma}\left(\sum_{i=1}^{n} x_i-n\mu\right) = 0\\\frac{\part}{\part\sigma^2}\ln L &=& -\frac{n}{2\sigma^2}+\frac{1}{2(\sigma^2)^2}\sum_{i=1}^{n}(x_i-\mu)^2 = 0  \\\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>We can solve</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\mu = \frac{1}{n}\sum_{i=1}^{n}x_i = \bar{x} \\\sigma^2 = \frac{1}{n}\sum_{i=1}^{n}(x_i-\mu)^2 = \frac{1}{n}\sum_{i=1}^{n}(x_i-\bar{x})^2</script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Estimator&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Estimator&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Estimator&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Estimator&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;Criterion&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Criterion&quot; class
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Mathematics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Classic Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/Classic-Statistics/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Probability" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Probability/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Stochastic" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Stochastic/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Normal Sample</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/12/Statistics%20normal%20sample/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/12/Statistics normal sample/</id>
    <published>2020-03-12T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T19:39:13.581Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Normal-Sample"><a href="#Normal-Sample" class="headerlink" title="Normal Sample"></a>Normal Sample</h1><h2 id="Normal-Distribution-Additivity"><a href="#Normal-Distribution-Additivity" class="headerlink" title="Normal Distribution Additivity"></a>Normal Distribution Additivity</h2><h3 id="Lemma-Convolution-Integral"><a href="#Lemma-Convolution-Integral" class="headerlink" title="Lemma: Convolution Integral"></a>Lemma: Convolution Integral</h3><h3 id="Additivity-of-normal-distribution"><a href="#Additivity-of-normal-distribution" class="headerlink" title="Additivity of normal distribution"></a>Additivity of normal distribution</h3><p>Suppose $X_i\sim N(\mu_i,\sigma_i^2)$, then </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">Z = X_1 + X_2+\cdots+X_n</script><p>subjects to the same distribution, and $Z\sim N(\mu_1+\mu_2+\cdots +\mu_n, \sigma_1^2+\sigma_2^2+\cdots+\sigma_n^2)$</p><p>Proof:</p><h2 id="Normal-Distribution-Sample"><a href="#Normal-Distribution-Sample" class="headerlink" title="Normal Distribution Sample"></a>Normal Distribution Sample</h2><h3 id="Mean-distribution"><a href="#Mean-distribution" class="headerlink" title="Mean distribution"></a>Mean distribution</h3><p>Suppose $X_i\sim N(\mu,\sigma^2)$, then </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\bar{X} & \sim & N(\mu, \frac{\sigma^2}{n}) \\\frac{\bar{X}-\mu}{\frac{\sigma}{\sqrt{n}}} & \sim & N(0,1)\end{eqnarray*}</script><h3 id="Variance-distribution-variance-sigma-2-is-unknown"><a href="#Variance-distribution-variance-sigma-2-is-unknown" class="headerlink" title="Variance distribution (variance $\sigma^2$ is unknown)"></a>Variance distribution (variance $\sigma^2$ is unknown)</h3><p>Suppose $X_i\sim N(\mu,\sigma^2)$, then </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{(n-1)S^2}{\sigma^2} \sim\chi^2(n-1)</script><p>$S^2$ is dependent to $\bar{X}$.</p><h3 id="Mean-distribution-mean-mu-is-unknown"><a href="#Mean-distribution-mean-mu-is-unknown" class="headerlink" title="Mean distribution (mean $\mu$ is unknown)"></a>Mean distribution (mean $\mu$ is unknown)</h3><p>Suppose $X_i\sim N(\mu,\sigma^2)$, then </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{\bar{X}-\mu}{\frac{S}{\sqrt{n}}} \sim t(n-1)</script><p>Proof:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\frac{\bar{X}-\mu}{\frac{\sigma}{\sqrt{n}}} & \sim & N(0,1) \\\frac{(n-1)S^2}{\sigma^2} & \sim & \chi^2(n-1) \\\frac{\frac{\bar{X}-\mu}{\frac{\sigma}{\sqrt{n}}}}{\sqrt{\frac{(n-1)S^2}{\sigma^2(n-1)}}} &=& \frac{\bar{X}-\mu}{\frac{S}{\sqrt{n}}} \sim t(n-1)\end{eqnarray*}</script><h3 id="Compare-with-two-random-variables-variance-sigma-2-is-unknown"><a href="#Compare-with-two-random-variables-variance-sigma-2-is-unknown" class="headerlink" title="Compare with two random variables (variance $\sigma^2$ is unknown)"></a>Compare with two random variables (variance $\sigma^2$ is unknown)</h3><p>Suppose $X_1, X_2, \cdots, X_{n_1} \sim N(\mu_1,\sigma_1^2)$ and $Y_1, Y_2, \cdots, Y_{n_2} \sim N(\mu_2,\sigma_2^2)$ , $X_i$ and $Y_i$ are sample and independent to each other. $\bar{X}$ and $\bar{Y}$ are sample mean, $S_1^2$ and $S_2^2$ are sample  variance, then</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{\frac{S_1^2}{S_2^2}}{\frac{\sigma_1^2}{\sigma_2^2}} \sim F(n_1-1,n_2-1)</script><h3 id="Compare-with-two-random-variables-mean-mu-is-unknown"><a href="#Compare-with-two-random-variables-mean-mu-is-unknown" class="headerlink" title="Compare with two random variables (mean $\mu $ is unknown)"></a>Compare with two random variables (mean $\mu $ is unknown)</h3><p>When $\sigma_1^2 = \sigma_2^2 =\sigma^2$, then</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{(\bar{X}-\bar{Y})-(\mu_1-\mu_2)}{S_w\sqrt{\frac{1}{n_1}+\frac{1}{n_2}}} \sim  t(n_1+n_2-2)</script><p>with $S_w^2 = \frac{(n_1-1)S_1^2+(n_2-1)S_2^2}{n_1+n_2-2}$</p><p><strong>Proof:</strong></p><p>$\bar{X}-\bar{Y}\sim N(\mu_1-\mu_2,\frac{\sigma_1^2}{n_1}+\frac{\sigma_2^2}{n_2})$</p><p>after standardizing:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{(\bar{X}-\bar{Y})-(\mu_1-\mu_2)}{\sqrt{\frac{\sigma_1^2}{n_1}+\frac{\sigma_2^2}{n_2}}} = \frac{(\bar{X}-\bar{Y})-(\mu_1-\mu_2)}{\sigma\sqrt{\frac{1}{n_1}+\frac{1}{n_2}}} \sim N(0,1)</script><p>For $\frac{(n_1-1)S_1^2}{\sigma_1^2} \sim\chi^2(n_1-1)$ and $\frac{(n_2-1)S_2^2}{\sigma_2^2} \sim\chi^2(n_2-1)$, then:  </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{(n_1-1)S_1^2 +(n_2-1)S_2^2  }{\sigma^2} \sim\chi^2(n_1+n_2-2)</script><p>by dividing:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{\frac{(\bar{X}-\bar{Y})-(\mu_1-\mu_2)}{\sigma\sqrt{\frac{1}{n_1}+\frac{1}{n_2}}}}{\sqrt{\frac{(n_1-1)S_1^2 +(n_2-1)S_2^2  }{\sigma^2(n_1+n_2-2)}}} = \frac{(\bar{X}-\bar{Y})-(\mu_1-\mu_2)}{S_w\sqrt{\frac{1}{n_1}+\frac{1}{n_2}}} \sim t(n_1+n_2+2)</script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Normal-Sample&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Normal-Sample&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Normal Sample&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Normal Sample&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;Normal-Distribution-A
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Mathematics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Classic Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/Classic-Statistics/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Probability" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Probability/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Stochastic" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Stochastic/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Central Limit Theorem</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/11/Statistics%20CLT/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/11/Statistics CLT/</id>
    <published>2020-03-11T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-11T21:44:20.280Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Central-Limit-Theorem"><a href="#Central-Limit-Theorem" class="headerlink" title="Central Limit Theorem"></a>Central Limit Theorem</h1><h2 id="IID-CLT"><a href="#IID-CLT" class="headerlink" title="IID CLT"></a>IID CLT</h2><p>For infinite independent random variable $X_1, X_2, …X_n, …$, which are from the identical distribution with the expectation $E(X_k) = \mu$, and variance $D(X_k) = \sigma^2$, then for $\forall ~ x$</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\lim_{n \to \infty} F_n(x)=\lim_{n \to \infty} P\left\{ \frac{\sum\limits_{k=1}^{n}X_k-n\mu}{\sqrt{n}\sigma} \leq x \right\} = \Phi(x)</script><p>where  $F_n(x)$ is the distribution function of $\frac{\sum\limits_{k=1}^{n}X_k-n\mu}{\sqrt{n}\sigma}$.</p><ul><li><p>The CLT implies that large iid experiment usually follows the normal distribution</p></li><li><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\sum\limits_{k=1}^{n}X_k \sim N(n\mu, n\sigma^2) \\\frac{1}{n}\sum\limits_{k=1}^{n}X_k \sim N(\mu, \frac{\sigma^2}{n})\end{eqnarray*}</script></li><li><p>Here, the sum of random variable $\sum\limits_{k=1}^{n}X_k$ matters.</p></li></ul><h2 id="De-Moivre-Laplace-Theorem"><a href="#De-Moivre-Laplace-Theorem" class="headerlink" title="De Moivre-Laplace Theorem"></a>De Moivre-Laplace Theorem</h2><p>For infinite independent random variable $\eta_1, \eta_2, …\eta_n, …$, which are from the <strong>binomial distribution</strong> $b(n,p)$, then for $\forall ~ x$</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\lim_{n \to \infty} P\left\{ \frac{\eta_n-np}{\sqrt{np(1-p)}} \leq x \right\} = \Phi(x)</script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Central-Limit-Theorem&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Central-Limit-Theorem&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Central Limit Theorem&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Central Limit Theorem&lt;/
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Mathematics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Classic Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/Classic-Statistics/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Probability" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Probability/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Stochastic" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Stochastic/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Useful Statistics and Sample Distribution</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/11/Statistics%20Useful%20statistics/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/11/Statistics Useful statistics/</id>
    <published>2020-03-11T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T00:19:49.706Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Useful-Statistics"><a href="#Useful-Statistics" class="headerlink" title="Useful Statistics"></a>Useful Statistics</h1><h2 id="Percentile"><a href="#Percentile" class="headerlink" title="Percentile"></a>Percentile</h2><p>For a sample $x_1, x_2,…,x_n,…$, the sample percentile denotes $x_p$:</p><ul><li>at least $np$ observations less than or equal $x_p$</li><li>at least $n(1-p)$ observations greater than or equal $x_p$</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}x_p = \begin{cases} x_{[np]+1} \\\frac{1}{2}[x_{np}+x_{np+1}]\end{cases}\end{eqnarray*}</script><h2 id="Sample-Mean"><a href="#Sample-Mean" class="headerlink" title="Sample Mean"></a>Sample Mean</h2><script type="math/tex; mode=display">E(\bar{X})=\frac{1}{n}\sum_{i=1}^{n}x_i=\frac{n\mu}{n}=\mu</script><h2 id="Sample-Variance"><a href="#Sample-Variance" class="headerlink" title="Sample Variance"></a>Sample Variance</h2><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}S^2&=&\frac{1}{n-1}\sum_{i=1}^{n}(X_i-\bar{X})^2 \\&=&\frac{1}{n-1}\left(\sum_{i=1}^{n}X_i^2-n\bar{X}^2\right)\end{eqnarray*}</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}S &=&\sqrt{\frac{1}{n-1}\left(\sum_{i=1}^{n}X_i^2-n\bar{X}^2\right)}\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>Check the unbiases:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">E(X_i^2)=D(X_i) + E(X_i)^2 = \sigma^2 + \mu^2 \\E(\bar{X}^2)=D(\bar{X})+E(\bar{X})^2 = \frac{\sigma^2}{n}+\mu^2\\E(X_i)=E(\bar{X}) = \mu</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}E(S^2) &=& E\left[\frac{1}{n-1}\left(\sum_{i=1}^{n}X_i^2-n\bar{X}^2\right)\right] \\&=& \frac{1}{n-1}E\left[\sum_{i=1}^{n}X_i^2\right]-\frac{n}{n-1}E[\bar{X}^2] \\&=& \frac{1}{n-1}\sum_{i=1}^{n}(\sigma^2+\mu^2)-\frac{n}{n-1}(\mu^2+\frac{\sigma^2}{n}) \\&=& \frac{n}{n-1}(\sigma^2-\frac{\sigma^2}{n}) \\&=&\sigma^2\end{eqnarray*}</script><h2 id="Moment"><a href="#Moment" class="headerlink" title="Moment"></a>Moment</h2><h3 id="k-origin-moment"><a href="#k-origin-moment" class="headerlink" title="k-origin moment"></a>k-origin moment</h3><h3 id="k-central-moment"><a href="#k-central-moment" class="headerlink" title="k-central moment"></a>k-central moment</h3><h1 id="Useful-Sampling-Distribution"><a href="#Useful-Sampling-Distribution" class="headerlink" title="Useful Sampling Distribution"></a>Useful Sampling Distribution</h1><h2 id="Chi-square-Distribution"><a href="#Chi-square-Distribution" class="headerlink" title="Chi-square Distribution"></a>Chi-square Distribution</h2><p>$X_1, X_2, …, X_n$ are from $N(0,1)$, then</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\chi^2=X_1^2+X_2^2+\cdots+X_n^2</script><p>follows $\chi^2$ distribution with freedom degree $n$ , denotes $\chi^2 \sim \chi^2(n)$</p><p>The probability density function is</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">f(x)=\begin{cases}\frac{1}{2^{\frac{n}{2}}\Gamma(\frac{n}{2})}x^{\frac{n}{2}-1}e^{-\frac{x}{2}},&  x>0 \\0 ,&x \leq 0\end{cases}</script><p>If $\chi^2\sim\chi^2(n)$, then</p><ul><li><p>$E(\chi^2)=n$</p></li><li><p>$D(\chi^2)=2n$</p></li></ul><h2 id="t-Distribution"><a href="#t-Distribution" class="headerlink" title="t Distribution"></a>t Distribution</h2><p>$X \sim N(0,1)$, $Y\sim\chi^2(n)$, $X$ is independent to $Y$, then</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">t = \frac{X}{\sqrt{\frac{Y}{n}}}</script><p>follows t distribution with freedom degree $n$.</p><p>The probability density function is</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">f(x)=\frac{\Gamma\left(\frac{n+1}{2}\right)}{\sqrt{\pi n}\Gamma(\frac{n}{2})}\left(1+\frac{x^2}{n}\right)^{-\frac{n+1}{2}}</script><p>If $t \sim t(n)$, then</p><ul><li>$E[t_{\alpha}(n)]=0$</li><li>$D[t_{\alpha}(n)]=\frac{n}{n-2}$</li></ul><h2 id="F-Distribution"><a href="#F-Distribution" class="headerlink" title="F Distribution"></a>F Distribution</h2><p>$U \sim \chi^2(n_1)$, $V\sim\chi^2(n_2)$, $U$ is independent to $V$, then</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F = \frac{\frac{U}{n_1}}{\frac{V}{n_2}}</script><p>follows F distribution with freedom degree $(n_1, n_2)$, denotes $F\sim F(n_1,n_2)$</p><p>The probability density function is</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">f(x)=\begin{cases}\frac{\Gamma[\frac{n_1+n_2}{2}](\frac{n_1}{n_2})^{\frac{n_1}{2}}x^{\frac{n_1}{2}-1}}{\Gamma(\frac{n_1}{2})\Gamma(\frac{n_2}{2})[1+\frac{n_1 x}{n_2}]^{\frac{n_1+n_2}{2}}},&  x>0 \\0 ,&x \leq 0\end{cases}</script><p>If $F\sim F(n_1, n_2)$, then</p><ul><li><p>$\frac{1}{F}\sim F(n_2,n_1)$</p></li><li><p>$F_{1-\alpha}(n_1,n_2)=\frac{1}{F_{\alpha}(n_2,n_1)}$</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Useful-Statistics&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Useful-Statistics&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Useful Statistics&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Useful Statistics&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;Perce
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Mathematics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Classic Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/Classic-Statistics/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Probability" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Probability/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Stochastic" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Stochastic/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Law of Large Numbers</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/11/Statistics%20LLN/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/11/Statistics LLN/</id>
    <published>2020-03-11T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-11T21:21:37.537Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Lemma-Chebyshev-Inequality"><a href="#Lemma-Chebyshev-Inequality" class="headerlink" title="Lemma: Chebyshev Inequality"></a>Lemma: Chebyshev Inequality</h1><p>For $E(X) = \mu$ and $D(x) = \sigma^2$, then</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">p\{| X-\mu| \geq \epsilon \} \leq\frac{\sigma^2}{\epsilon^2}</script><p>Proof:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}p\{| X-\mu| \geq \epsilon \} &=& \int_{|x-\mu|\geq\epsilon}f(x)dx \\&\leq& \int_{|x-\mu|\geq\epsilon} \frac{|x-\mu|^2}{\epsilon^2} f(x)dx \\&\leq& \frac{1}{\epsilon^2}\int_{-\infty}^{\infty} (x-\mu)^2 f(x)dx \\&=& \frac{\sigma^2}{\epsilon^2}\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>which also implies</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">p\{| X-\mu| < \epsilon \} \geq 1- \frac{\sigma^2}{\epsilon^2}</script><h1 id="Law-of-Large-Numbers"><a href="#Law-of-Large-Numbers" class="headerlink" title="Law of Large Numbers"></a>Law of Large Numbers</h1><h2 id="Khinchin-LLN"><a href="#Khinchin-LLN" class="headerlink" title="Khinchin LLN"></a>Khinchin LLN</h2><p>For infinite independent random variable $X_1, X_2, …$, which are from the identical distribution with the expectation $E(x_k) = \mu$, then for $\forall ~ \epsilon$</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\lim_{n \to \infty}P\left\{ \left| \frac{1}{n}\sum_{k=1}^{n}X_k-\mu \right| <\epsilon\right\} = 1</script><p>When the $n$ is close to positive infinity, $\frac{1}{n}\sum_{k=1}^{n}X_k$ is close to $\mu$, which is the expectation of $X$ </p><p>Proof:</p><p>Assume the variance exist $D(X) = \sigma^2$, then</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}E\left(\frac{1}{n}\sum_{k=1}^nX_k\right) &=& \frac{1}{n}\sum_{k=1}^nE(X_k) \\&=& \frac{1}{n}\times n\mu \\&=& \mu\end{eqnarray*}</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}D\left(\frac{1}{n}\sum_{k=1}^nX_k\right) &=& \frac{1}{n^2}\sum_{k=1}^nD(X_k) \\&=& \frac{1}{n^2}\times n\sigma^2 \\&=& \frac{\sigma^2}{n}\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>use the Chebyshev Inequity:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}1 \geq  P\left\{ \left| \frac{1}{n}\sum_{k=1}^{n}X_k-\mu \right| <\epsilon\right\} \geq 1-\frac{\frac{\sigma^2}{n}}{\epsilon^2}\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>when $n\to\infty$, then we can draw the conclusion.</p><h2 id="Bernoulli-LLN"><a href="#Bernoulli-LLN" class="headerlink" title="Bernoulli LLN"></a>Bernoulli LLN</h2><p>Assume that $f_A$ is the frequency of event $A$ happening in $n$ times independent repeated experiment,  and $p$ is the probability of event $A$ happening in each experiment, then for $\forall ~ \epsilon&gt; 0$</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\lim_{n \to \infty}P\left\{ \left| \frac{f_A}{n}-p \right| <\epsilon\right\} = 1</script><p>Proof:</p><p>From the Khinchin LLN</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Lemma-Chebyshev-Inequality&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Lemma-Chebyshev-Inequality&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Lemma: Chebyshev Inequality&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Lemma: 
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Mathematics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Classic Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Statistics/Classic-Statistics/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Probability" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Probability/"/>
    
      <category term="Statistics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Statistics/"/>
    
      <category term="Stochastic" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Stochastic/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Credit Products</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/03/04/Financial%20Risk%20Management%20Credit/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/03/04/Financial Risk Management Credit/</id>
    <published>2020-03-04T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-13T17:36:34.586Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions of Credit Product and risks.</p><h1 id="Credit-Market"><a href="#Credit-Market" class="headerlink" title="Credit Market"></a>Credit Market</h1><p>Credit market risk reflects the yield spread over the benchmark or risk free rate for a specific issuer, which is a gauge of the probability of default and/or changes in the expected loss given default.<br>In order to properly evaluate, classify and understand credit market risk drivers, it is important to have insight into the types of credit instruments available, distinguish between securitized and non securitized forms of credit risk and understand direct and indirect credit exposures</p><h2 id="Loan"><a href="#Loan" class="headerlink" title="Loan"></a>Loan</h2><h3 id="Floating-rate-notes"><a href="#Floating-rate-notes" class="headerlink" title="Floating rate notes"></a>Floating rate notes</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}PV &=& \frac{\frac{(\text{Index}+\text{QM})\times \text{FV}}{m}}{1+\frac{\text{Index} + \text{DM}}{m}} + \frac{\frac{(\text{Index}+\text{QM})\times \text{FV}}{m}}{(1+\frac{\text{Index} + \text{DM}}{m})^2} +... +\frac{\frac{(\text{Index}+\text{QM})\times \text{FV}}{m}+\text{FV}}{(1+\frac{\text{Index} + \text{DM}}{m})^N}\end{eqnarray*}</script><h3 id="Mortgage"><a href="#Mortgage" class="headerlink" title="Mortgage"></a>Mortgage</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">x = F_0 \times\frac{r(1+r)^n}{(1+r)^n-1}</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_t = F_{t-1}+\frac{R}{12}\times F_{t-1}-x</script><p>Principle:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_t - F_{t-1}</script><h2 id="Securitization"><a href="#Securitization" class="headerlink" title="Securitization"></a>Securitization</h2><h3 id="Benefit-of-Securitization"><a href="#Benefit-of-Securitization" class="headerlink" title="Benefit of Securitization"></a>Benefit of Securitization</h3><p>Cost Efficiency for Issuers Firms</p><p>Asset Related Risk Transfer</p><p>Investor Diversification, Risk Sharing and Liquidity</p><h3 id="Risk-of-Securitization"><a href="#Risk-of-Securitization" class="headerlink" title="Risk of Securitization"></a>Risk of Securitization</h3><p>Transaction Complexity</p><p>Credit / Default Risk</p><p>Prepayment Reinvestment Early Amortization</p><p>Moral Hazard Conflicts of Interest</p><h2 id="Credit-Default-Swap"><a href="#Credit-Default-Swap" class="headerlink" title="Credit Default Swap"></a>Credit Default Swap</h2><h2 id="CXA"><a href="#CXA" class="headerlink" title="CXA"></a>CXA</h2><h3 id="CVA"><a href="#CVA" class="headerlink" title="CVA"></a>CVA</h3><p><strong>Credit valuation adjustment (CVA) is the present value of credit risk for a loan, bond or derivative obligation</strong>. The CVA calculation for a financial exposure is a function of <strong>expected exposure (EE)</strong>, <strong>recovery rate (RR)</strong>, <strong>loss given default (LGD)</strong>, the <strong>probability of default (POD)</strong> to arrive at an <strong>expected loss (EL)</strong>, and a discount factor to arrive at the present value of expected loss. Steps in the process are as follows:</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/03/05/1SO9Qxo54Ywkp27.png" alt="cva.png"></p><h3 id="Example"><a href="#Example" class="headerlink" title="Example:"></a>Example:</h3><p>Consider exposure to a borrower who must deliver a zero-coupon government bond with a yield of 5% maturing in four years, assuming a recovery rate of 40% and probability of default per period of 1.25%. Following the steps on our prior slide:</p><p>Expected Exposure:</p><p>Recovery:</p><p>Loss given Default:</p><p>Probability of Default:</p><p>Expected Loss</p><p>PV of Expected Loss:</p><div class="table-container"><table><thead><tr><th>EE</th><th>Recovery</th><th>LGD</th><th>POD</th><th>POS</th><th>EL</th><th>DF</th><th>PV</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr></tbody></table></div><h2 id="Credit-Scoring"><a href="#Credit-Scoring" class="headerlink" title="Credit Scoring"></a>Credit Scoring</h2><p><strong>Credit scores and ratings</strong> are used by lenders in deciding whether to extend credit to a borrower and in determining contract terms Credit scores are used primarily by lenders for small and medium sized enterprises as well as retail customers Credit ratings are used by credit rating agencies in the wholesale market for bonds issued by private and public entities as well as for asset backed securities (ABS)</p><h3 id="advantage"><a href="#advantage" class="headerlink" title="advantage"></a>advantage</h3><p>shortcut to avoid risk </p><h3 id="disadvantage"><a href="#disadvantage" class="headerlink" title="disadvantage"></a>disadvantage</h3><p>lag indicator</p><h2 id="Sovereign-credit-risk"><a href="#Sovereign-credit-risk" class="headerlink" title="Sovereign credit risk"></a>Sovereign credit risk</h2><p>Key differences in sovereign credit risk include the protection against bankruptcy, protections<br>against creditors as well as unique sources of repayment such as the ability to tax Bankruptcy.<br>versus sovereign debt restructuring renegotiation Bankruptcy is typically protected by national law and most defaults are resolved via debt restructuring and/or renegotiation.</p><p><strong>Debt/GDP Ratio</strong> Similar to ratios for private borrowers, this statistic is widely seen as a barometer for a country’s ability to service its interest and repay debts given that GDP may be as a proxy for a country’s “balance sheet” measuring overall economic activity subject to taxation</p><h1 id="Credit-Portfolio-Management"><a href="#Credit-Portfolio-Management" class="headerlink" title="Credit Portfolio Management"></a>Credit Portfolio Management</h1><p>Credit portfolio management involves aggregating information across obligors to classify, quantify, manage, report and mitigate (or securitize) risks</p><p>The key question is to estimate default probabilities, which can be estimated via:</p><ul><li>Historical data</li><li>Credit Spreads</li><li>Structural Credit / Reduced form model<ul><li>Structural Model</li><li>Reduced Form Model</li><li>Market Consolidation<ul><li>MSCI: Risk-Metrics</li><li>Moody: KMV</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><h2 id="Z-score"><a href="#Z-score" class="headerlink" title="Z-score"></a>Z-score</h2><h3 id="Altman’s-Z-Score-Model"><a href="#Altman’s-Z-Score-Model" class="headerlink" title="Altman’s Z-Score Model"></a>Altman’s Z-Score Model</h3><h3 id="Accounting-Ratios"><a href="#Accounting-Ratios" class="headerlink" title="Accounting Ratios"></a>Accounting Ratios</h3><p>$X_1 = \frac{\text{Working Capital}}{\text{Total Assets}}$</p><p>$X_2 = \frac{\text{Working Capital}}{\text{Total Assets}}$</p><p>$X_3 = \frac{\text{Working Capital}}{\text{Total Assets}}$</p><p>$X_4 = \frac{\text{Working Capital}}{\text{Total Assets}}$</p><p>$X_5 = \frac{\text{Working Capital}}{\text{Total Assets}}$</p><p>$Z = 1.2X_1 + 1.4X_2 +3.3X_3 +0.4X_4 +0.99X_5$</p><h3 id="Conclusion"><a href="#Conclusion" class="headerlink" title="Conclusion"></a>Conclusion</h3><p>$Z&gt;3.0$</p><p>$2.7&lt;Z&lt;3.0$</p><p>$1.8&lt;Z&lt;2.7$</p><p>$Z&lt;1.8$</p><h2 id="Default-Probabilities"><a href="#Default-Probabilities" class="headerlink" title="Default Probabilities"></a>Default Probabilities</h2><h3 id="Historical-Default-Probabilities"><a href="#Historical-Default-Probabilities" class="headerlink" title="Historical Default Probabilities"></a>Historical Default Probabilities</h3><p>unconditional</p><h3 id="Hazard-Rate"><a href="#Hazard-Rate" class="headerlink" title="Hazard Rate"></a>Hazard Rate</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">Q(t)=1-e^{-\lambda(t)t}</script><h3 id="Ratings-Migration"><a href="#Ratings-Migration" class="headerlink" title="Ratings Migration"></a>Ratings Migration</h3><p>Example:</p><p>The rating agencies report transition matrices based on historical experience The example below shows the probabilities of a rating migrating over the course of the next twelve months For example, an A rated issuer has a 91.8% probability of remaining at that level, a 0 1 probability of moving up to AAA, a 1.4% probability of moving up to AA, a 3.6% probability of moving down to BBB, 2.4% down to BB and 0.7% to B</p><div class="table-container"><table><thead><tr><th></th><th></th><th></th><th></th><th></th><th></th><th></th><th></th><th></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td><td></td></tr></tbody></table></div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions of Credit Product and risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 i
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Economics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/"/>
    
      <category term="Finance" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/"/>
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/Risk-Management/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Risk-Management/"/>
    
      <category term="NYU" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/NYU/"/>
    
      <category term="FRM" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/FRM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Applied English in Health</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/27/EnglishPod%20Health/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/27/EnglishPod Health/</id>
    <published>2020-02-27T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-27T14:50:59.565Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Disease"><a href="#Disease" class="headerlink" title="Disease"></a>Disease</h1><h2 id="145c-Chicken-Pox"><a href="#145c-Chicken-Pox" class="headerlink" title="145c - Chicken Pox"></a>145c - Chicken Pox</h2><ul><li>itchy<ul><li>to itch, to scratch</li></ul></li><li>lightheaded<ul><li>dizzy, faint</li></ul></li><li>contagious<ul><li>flu is very contagious</li><li>The sickness that is going around the office is very contagious</li></ul></li><li>a rash<ul><li>a part of skin that becomes irritated or uncomfortable<ul><li>poison ivy, poison oak</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>biohazard<ul><li>biology + dangerous</li><li>Ebola virus is a biohazard</li></ul></li><li>coming down with<ul><li>I am coming down with a cold:  starting to feel sick<ul><li>I think I am coming down with something</li><li>coming down with a cough</li></ul></li></ul></li><li>in the meantime</li><li>blow things out of proportion<ul><li>exaggerate</li><li>siblings souse or bosses, blow things out of proportion. It’s not a big deal</li></ul></li><li>oatmeal bath: home remedies, home cures for the itchiness<ul><li>it’s calming and smooth</li></ul></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Disease&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Disease&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Disease&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Disease&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;145c-Chicken-Pox&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#145c-Chicken-Pox&quot;
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Languages" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Languages/"/>
    
      <category term="English" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Languages/English/"/>
    
      <category term="EnglishPod" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Languages/English/EnglishPod/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="Speaking" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Speaking/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Applied English in Sports</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/23/EnglishPod%20Sports/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/23/EnglishPod Sports/</id>
    <published>2020-02-23T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-23T22:51:29.199Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Chess"><a href="#Chess" class="headerlink" title="Chess"></a>Chess</h1><h2 id="139b-playing-chess"><a href="#139b-playing-chess" class="headerlink" title="139b - playing chess"></a>139b - playing chess</h2><ul><li>pawn<ul><li>something that is not very important and is used to distract an opponent<ul><li>one space forward</li></ul></li><li>he used her as a pawn in his little game</li></ul></li><li>rook: towers from a castle<ul><li>the whole board</li></ul></li><li>bishop: go only diagonally<ul><li>slanted line</li></ul></li><li>knight: L sharpe<ul><li>move three spaces and in a shape of an L</li></ul></li><li><p>Queen, King</p><ul><li>queen moves as many spaces as she wants in any direction</li><li>queen moves one space in any direction he wants</li></ul></li><li><p>move diagonally</p><ul><li>a diagonal line: 45 degree</li></ul></li><li><p>a little horsy</p><ul><li>a cute way of saying horse</li></ul></li><li><p>capture</p><ul><li>take and keep for yourself</li><li>capture the flag </li><li>capture another piece / eat the piece</li></ul></li><li>checkmate<ul><li>check: I can take your king if I want to - move</li><li>checkmate: the end all. I trapped you and I win</li></ul></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Chess&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Chess&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Chess&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Chess&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&quot;139b-playing-chess&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#139b-playing-chess&quot; cla
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Languages" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Languages/"/>
    
      <category term="English" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Languages/English/"/>
    
      <category term="EnglishPod" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Languages/English/EnglishPod/"/>
    
    
      <category term="English" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/English/"/>
    
      <category term="Speaking" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Speaking/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Linear Algebra Basics</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/22/Algebra%20Linear%20Algebra%20Basics/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/22/Algebra Linear Algebra Basics/</id>
    <published>2020-02-22T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-23T21:15:12.131Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This note contains basic knowledge and summary of Linear Algebra, including vector, matrix, linear transform etc. The main ideas come from 3Blue1Brown.</p><h1 id="vector"><a href="#vector" class="headerlink" title="vector"></a>vector</h1><h2 id="basis"><a href="#basis" class="headerlink" title="basis"></a>basis</h2><h2 id="transformation"><a href="#transformation" class="headerlink" title="transformation"></a>transformation</h2><h3 id="linear-transformation"><a href="#linear-transformation" class="headerlink" title="linear transformation"></a>linear transformation</h3><ul><li>$90^\circ$ counterclockwise rotate</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}0 & -1 \\1 & 0\end{array}\right]</script><ul><li>$90^\circ$ clockwise rotate</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}0 & 1 \\-1 & 0\end{array}\right]</script><ul><li>rightward shear</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}1 & 1 \\0 & 1\end{array}\right]</script><ul><li>leftward shear</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}1 & -1 \\0 & 1\end{array}\right]</script><ul><li>identical transformation</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}1 & 0 \\0 & 1\end{array}\right]</script><h3 id="linear-dependent-and-independent"><a href="#linear-dependent-and-independent" class="headerlink" title="linear dependent and independent"></a>linear dependent and independent</h3><h2 id="matrix-multiplication"><a href="#matrix-multiplication" class="headerlink" title="matrix multiplication"></a>matrix multiplication</h2><ul><li>$2 \times 1$ example</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{cc}a & b \\c & d\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{c}x \\y\end{array}\right] =x \left[\begin{array}{c}a \\b\end{array}\right] + y \left[\begin{array}{c}c \\d\end{array}\right] =\left[\begin{array}{c}ax+cy \\bx+dy\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script><ul><li>$2 \times 2$ example</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{cc}a & b \\c & d\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}e & f \\g & h\end{array}\right]=\left[\begin{array}{cc}ae+bg & af+bh \\ce+dg & cf+dh\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script><ul><li><p>$3 \times 1$ example</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{ccc}0 & 1 & 2 \\3 & 4 & 5 \\6 & 7 & 8\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{ccc}x \\y \\z\end{array}\right]=x \left[\begin{array}{ccc}0 \\3 \\6\end{array}\right] + y \left[\begin{array}{ccc}1 \\4 \\7\end{array}\right] + z \left[\begin{array}{ccc}2 \\5 \\8\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script></li><li><p>$3 \times 3$ example</p></li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{ccc}0 & 1 & 2 \\3 & 4 & 5 \\6 & 7 & 8\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{ccc}x_1 & x_2 & x_3 \\y_1 & y_2 & y_3 \\z_1 & z_2 & z_3\end{array}\right]=\left[\begin{array}{ccc}0x_1+1y_1+2z_1 & 0x_2+1y_2+2z_2 & 0x_3+1y_3+2z_3 \\3x_1+4y_1+5z_1 & 3x_2+4y_2+5z_2 & 3x_3+4y_3+5z_3 \\6x_1+7y_1+8z_1 & 6x_2+7y_2+8z_2 & 6x_3+7y_3+8z_3 \\\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script><h3 id="determinant"><a href="#determinant" class="headerlink" title="determinant"></a>determinant</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left|\begin{array}{ccc}0 & 1 & 2 \\3 & 4 & 5 \\6 & 7 & 8\end{array}\right|=0 \left|\begin{array}{cc}4 & 5 \\7 & 8\end{array}\right| - 1 \left|\begin{array}{ccc}3 & 6 \\5 & 8\end{array}\right| + 2 \left|\begin{array}{ccc}3 & 4 \\6 & 7 \\\end{array}\right|\end{eqnarray*}</script><h1 id="linear-system-of-equations"><a href="#linear-system-of-equations" class="headerlink" title="linear system of equations"></a>linear system of equations</h1><p>Consider a linear system of equation:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}0x + 1y + 2z &=& -3 \\3x + 4y + 5z &=& 0 \\6x + 7y + 8z &=& 2\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>rewrite them in matrix format:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{ccc}0 & 1 & 2 \\3 & 4 & 5 \\6 & 7 & 8\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{ccc}x \\y \\z\end{array}\right]=\left[\begin{array}{ccc}-3 \\0 \\2\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>we can abstract them as this:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">A \vec x = \vec v</script><p>here $A$ is a linear transformation. we need to find  $\vec x$ to match $\vec a$ after the linear transformation.</p><h3 id="inverse-matrix"><a href="#inverse-matrix" class="headerlink" title="inverse matrix"></a>inverse matrix</h3><p>find a transformation inverse the original transformation</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">A^{-1}A=\left[\begin{array}{cc} 1 & 0 \\ 0 & 1\end{array}\right]</script><h3 id="rank"><a href="#rank" class="headerlink" title="rank"></a>rank</h3><p>the number of dimensions in the output of a transformation</p><h3 id="column-space"><a href="#column-space" class="headerlink" title="column space"></a>column space</h3><p>column space is the span of columns （以列为基向量的空间）</p><p>The rank is the number of dimensions in the column space. (full rank)</p><p>zero vector is always in the column space. </p><h3 id="null-space-and-kernel"><a href="#null-space-and-kernel" class="headerlink" title="null space and kernel"></a>null space and kernel</h3><ul><li>For a full rank transformation, <strong>the only vector</strong> that lands at the origin is the <strong>zero vector itself</strong>.</li><li>For matrices that aren’t full rank, they will be squish to a smaller dimension, which means a series of vectors will land at the origin. </li><li><p>This set of vectors that lands on the origin is called the <strong>null space</strong> or <strong>kernel of the matrix</strong>.</p><ul><li>the space of all vectors become null, and they land on the zero vectors.</li></ul></li><li><p>For linear system equations:</p><ul><li><strong>When $\vec v$ is a zero vector, then the null space gives you all of the possible solutions</strong> to the equation.</li></ul></li></ul><h2 id="non-square-matrices"><a href="#non-square-matrices" class="headerlink" title="non-square matrices"></a>non-square matrices</h2><p>A 3 by 2 matrix means mapping two dimensions to three dimensions</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{ccc}0 & 1 \\3 & 4 \\6 & 7\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script><ul><li><p>Two columns indicate that the input space has two basis vectors. </p></li><li><p>Three rows indicate that the landing spots of each of those basis vectors is described with three separate coordinates.</p></li></ul><p>Similarly,  a 2 by 3 matrix means mapping three dimensions to two dimensions.</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{ccc}0 & 1 & 2 \\3 & 4 & 5\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>A 1 by 2 matrix means mapping a surface to an axis(number line).</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\left[\begin{array}{ccc}0 & 1\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray*}</script><h1 id="dot-product"><a href="#dot-product" class="headerlink" title="dot product"></a>dot product</h1><h2 id="rules"><a href="#rules" class="headerlink" title="rules"></a>rules</h2><ul><li>order doesn’t matter.</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\vec w \cdot \vec v = \left[\begin{array}{cc}-1 \\2\end{array}\right] \cdot\left[\begin{array}{cc}5 \\7\end{array}\right] =-1 \times 5 + 2 \times 7 = 9\end{eqnarray*}</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\vec u \cdot \vec v = \left[\begin{array}{cc}u_x & u_y\end{array}\right] \cdot\left[\begin{array}{cc}x \\y\end{array}\right] =u_x\cdot x + u_y\cdot y\end{eqnarray*}</script><h3 id="projection"><a href="#projection" class="headerlink" title="projection"></a>projection</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec u \cdot \vec v >0</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec u \cdot \vec v = 0</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec u \cdot \vec v <0</script><h3 id="duality"><a href="#duality" class="headerlink" title="duality"></a>duality</h3><p>1 $\times$ 2 matrices and 2d vectors</p><p>dot product is corresponding to a unique linear transformation from multiple-dimension space to 1-d space</p><h1 id="cross-product"><a href="#cross-product" class="headerlink" title="cross product"></a>cross product</h1><h2 id="rules-1"><a href="#rules-1" class="headerlink" title="rules"></a>rules</h2><ul><li>order matters, which should be the same order as basis vector</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec u \times \vec v = -\vec v \times \vec u</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec u \times \vec v = \left[\begin{array}{cc}-1 \\2\end{array}\right] \times\left[\begin{array}{cc}5 \\7\end{array}\right] =\left|\begin{array}{cc}-1 & 5 \\2 & 7\end{array}\right| = -7-10 = -17</script><h3 id="area"><a href="#area" class="headerlink" title="area"></a>area</h3><p>the determinant of the matrix combined by two vectors is the ratio of the scaled area</p><ul><li>more perpendicular -&gt; larger area of cross product</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display"></script><h3 id="a-new-vector"><a href="#a-new-vector" class="headerlink" title="a new vector"></a>a new vector</h3><p>the outcome of cross product is a vector:</p><ul><li>length is the area of parallelogram</li><li>direction is perpendicular to the parallelogram based on right-hand rule</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec v \times \vec w = \left[\begin{array}{cc}v_1 \\v_2 \\v_3\end{array}\right] \times\left[\begin{array}{cc}w_1 \\w_2 \\w_3\end{array}\right] =\left|\begin{array}{cc}i & v_1 & w_1 \\j & v_2 & w_2 \\k & v_3 & w_3\end{array}\right| = i(v_2w_3-v3w2)+j(v_1w_3-v_3w_1)+k(v_1w_2-v_2w_1)</script><h2 id="meaning"><a href="#meaning" class="headerlink" title="meaning"></a>meaning</h2><p>Define a linear function</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">f\left(\left[\begin{array}{cc}x \\y \\z\end{array}\right]\right) =\left|\begin{array}{cc}x & v_1 & w_1 \\y & v_2 & w_2 \\z & v_3 & w_3\end{array}\right|=\left[\begin{array}{ccc}p_1 \\p_2 \\p_3\end{array}\right] \cdot\left[\begin{array}{ccc}x \\y \\z\end{array}\right]</script><p>which is the volume of a parallelepiped</p><p>which is also a 3d to 1d linear transformation</p><h1 id="basis-transformation"><a href="#basis-transformation" class="headerlink" title="basis transformation"></a>basis transformation</h1><h2 id="coordinate-system-and-basis-vectors"><a href="#coordinate-system-and-basis-vectors" class="headerlink" title="coordinate system and basis vectors"></a>coordinate system and basis vectors</h2><p>The ordinary basis vectors under the common coordinate system</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">i=\left[\begin{array}{cc}1 \\0\end{array}\right],~j=\left[\begin{array}{cc}0 \\1\end{array}\right]</script><p>imagine a new pair of vectors, which are defined by the ordinary basis vectors (or common coordinate system), and they are the basis vectors of a  new coordinate system:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec b_1=\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 \\1\end{array}\right],~\vec b_2=\left[\begin{array}{cc}-1 \\1\end{array}\right]</script><p>in the new coordinate system, $\vec b_1$ and $\vec b_2$ are the basis vector.</p><h2 id="vectors-in-different-basis"><a href="#vectors-in-different-basis" class="headerlink" title="vectors in different basis"></a>vectors in different basis</h2><h3 id="from-new-coordinates-to-ordinary-coordinates"><a href="#from-new-coordinates-to-ordinary-coordinates" class="headerlink" title="from new coordinates to ordinary coordinates"></a>from new coordinates to ordinary coordinates</h3><p>Consider such an example. The $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>-1 \\<br>2<br>\end{array}\right]$ is a vector in the new coordinate system (using the new basis $\vec b_1$ and $\vec b_2 $), and $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>-4 \\<br>1<br>\end{array}\right]$ is the corresponding (same) vector in the ordinary coordinate system (using the ordinary basis $i$ and $j$).</p><p>Now, there are two roles of the transformation matrix:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right]</script><p>First, <strong>numerically</strong>,  this is the matrix which is used to compute the vector from the new basis to the ordinary basis</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}-1 \\2\end{array}\right]=-1\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 \\1\end{array}\right]+2\left[\begin{array}{cc}-1 \\1\end{array}\right]=\left[\begin{array}{cc}-4 \\1\end{array}\right]</script><p>but <strong>geometrically</strong>, this matrix can be regarded as a transformation matrix from the ordinary basis to the new basis:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right] = \left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}1 & 0 \\0 & 1\end{array}\right]</script><p>Here, the key point is the vectors shares the same coordinates in the common coordinate system and the new coordinate system are not the same vector. They only share the same signs.</p><p>The above is used to compute corresponding vectors using the ordinary basis <strong>if we know a vector in the new coordinate system</strong>. Just take <strong>the new coordinate basis matrix</strong> and <strong>the coordinate vector</strong>,and do the matrix-vector multiplication:</p><h3 id="from-ordinary-coordinates-to-new-coordinates"><a href="#from-ordinary-coordinates-to-new-coordinates" class="headerlink" title="from ordinary coordinates to new coordinates"></a>from ordinary coordinates to new coordinates</h3><p>Inversely, if we know a vector (in the common coordinate system) which is $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>3 \\<br>2<br>\end{array}\right]$ and we want to compute the corresponding vector in the new coordinate system, which is defined by  $\vec b_1$ and $\vec b_2$ , then we should do the following things:</p><ol><li>take the inverse of the new basis matrix</li></ol><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right]^{-1} =\left[\begin{array}{cc}\frac{1}{3} & \frac{1}{3} \\-\frac{1}{3} & \frac{2}{3}\end{array}\right]</script><ol><li>compute the matrix and vector product:<script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}\frac{1}{3} & \frac{1}{3} \\-\frac{1}{3} & \frac{2}{3}\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}3 \\2\end{array}\right] = \left[\begin{array}{cc}\frac{5}{3} \\\frac{1}{3}\end{array}\right]</script></li></ol><p>Then, the corresponding (same) vector in the new coordinate system is $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>\frac{5}{3} \\<br>\frac{1}{3}<br>\end{array}\right]$.</p><h3 id="Summary"><a href="#Summary" class="headerlink" title="Summary"></a>Summary</h3><p>$A$ is the new basis matrix written in the ordinary coordinates, like $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>2 &amp; -1 \\<br>1 &amp; 1<br>\end{array}\right]$,</p><p>and $ \vec x $ is a vector written in the new coordinates, like $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>-1 \\<br>2<br>\end{array}\right]$,</p><p>then $ \vec v$ is the vector written in the ordinary coordinates, like $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>-4 \\<br>1<br>\end{array}\right]$:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">A\vec x=\vec v</script><p>And</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\vec x=A^{-1}\vec v</script><h2 id="transformation-matrix-in-different-basis"><a href="#transformation-matrix-in-different-basis" class="headerlink" title="transformation matrix in different basis"></a>transformation matrix in different basis</h2><p>Consider such an example. In the ordinary basis, the $90^\circ$ counterclockwise rotate is </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}0 & -1 \\1 & 0\end{array}\right]</script><p>But in the coordinate system defined by $\vec b_1$ and $\vec b_2$ , the $90^\circ$ counterclockwise rotate should be</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right]^{-1}\left[\begin{array}{cc}0 & -1 \\1 & 0\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right] = \left[\begin{array}{cc}\frac{1}{3} & -\frac{2}{3} \\\frac{5}{3} & -\frac{1}{3}\end{array}\right]</script><p>Therefore, if the $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>1 \\<br>2<br>\end{array}\right]$ is a vector in the new coordinate system (using the new basis $\vec b_1$ and $\vec b_2 $), and compute:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray}\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right]^{-1}\left[\begin{array}{cc}0 & -1 \\1 & 0\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\1 & 1\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}1 \\2\end{array}\right] = \left[\begin{array}{cc}\frac{1}{3} & -\frac{2}{3} \\\frac{5}{3} & -\frac{1}{3}\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}1 \\2\end{array}\right] = \left[\begin{array}{cc}-1 \\1\end{array}\right]\end{eqnarray}</script><p>then the $\left[\begin{array}{cc}<br>-1 \\<br>1<br>\end{array}\right]$ is a vector in the new coordinate system.</p><h3 id="summary"><a href="#summary" class="headerlink" title="summary"></a>summary</h3><p>$A^{-1}MA$ suggests a mathematical sort of empathy. And $M$ is a kind of transformation in the ordinary basis.</p><h1 id="Eigenvectors-and-Eigenvalues"><a href="#Eigenvectors-and-Eigenvalues" class="headerlink" title="Eigenvectors and Eigenvalues"></a>Eigenvectors and Eigenvalues</h1><p>The eigenvectors are the vectors land in the line spanned by the transformation.</p><p>The eigenvalues are the scaling ratios associated with the eigenvectors.</p><p>The equation:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">A\vec v = \lambda \vec v</script><p>$A$ is the transformation matrix, $\vec v$ is the eigenvector, and $\lambda$ is the eigenvalue. Take a 3 dimension as an example:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray}A\vec v &=& \lambda \vec v \\A\vec v &=& \left[\begin{array}{ccc}\lambda & 0 & 0 \\0 & \lambda & 0 \\0 & 0 & \lambda\end{array}\right] \vec v \\A\vec v &=& (\lambda I)\vec v \\(A-\lambda I)\vec v &=& \vec 0 \\\end{eqnarray}</script><p>And it would be something like this:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{ccc}3-\lambda & 1 & 4 \\1 & 5-\lambda & 9 \\2 & 6 & 5-\lambda\end{array}\right] \vec v = \vec0</script><p>we need to find a $\vec v$ which satisfies the equation. zero vector always satisfies.</p><p>Only the <strong>squishification</strong>, which is a transformation from high dimension to low dimension, can be associated with a non-zero vectors such that the product of transformation matrix and the vector to be zero vector.</p><p>Therefore, we need to find a $\lambda$ such that the determinant of the transformation matrix is 0:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">|A-\lambda I| = 0</script><p>But not every matrix has eigenvectors and eigenvalue in the real number field, (They will have some meaning in the complex plane.) such as rotation.</p><ul><li>A single eigenvalue can have more that a line full of eigenvectors, such as scaling transformation.</li></ul><h2 id="eigen-basis"><a href="#eigen-basis" class="headerlink" title="eigen-basis"></a>eigen-basis</h2><p>A diagonal matrix can be regarded as a set of eigen-basis (each column is a component of the basis.)</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">E^{-1}AE = diag</script><h1 id="vector-space"><a href="#vector-space" class="headerlink" title="vector space"></a>vector space</h1><p>determinant and eigenvectors don’t care about the coordinate system.</p><h2 id="Linear-concepts"><a href="#Linear-concepts" class="headerlink" title="Linear concepts"></a>Linear concepts</h2><h3 id="Additivity"><a href="#Additivity" class="headerlink" title="Additivity"></a>Additivity</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">L(\vec v + \vec w) = L(\vec v) + L(\vec w)</script><h3 id="Scaling-first-order-homogeneous"><a href="#Scaling-first-order-homogeneous" class="headerlink" title="Scaling (first order homogeneous)"></a>Scaling (first order homogeneous)</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">L(c \vec v) = cL(\vec v)</script><p>Linear transformations preserve the operations of vector addition and scalar multiplication.</p><p><strong>Geometrically</strong>, it means that grid lines remain <strong>parallel</strong> and <strong>evenly spaced</strong>.</p><h3 id="derivative-is-linear"><a href="#derivative-is-linear" class="headerlink" title="derivative is linear"></a>derivative is linear</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{d}{dx}(x^3+x^2)=\frac{d}{dx}(x^3)+\frac{d}{dx}(x^2)</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{d}{dx}(4x^3) = 4\frac{d}{dx}(x^3)</script><p>For a space with all the polynomials:</p><p>The basis functions are</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">b_0(x) = 1 \\b_1(x) = x \\b_2(x) = x^2 \\\vdots \\b_n(x) = x^n \\</script><p>they are infinitely many, which means that if we treat them as a point in the space, they will have infinite coordinates. For example:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">1x^2+3x+5 =\left[\begin{array}{c}5 \\3 \\1 \\0 \\0 \\\vdots\end{array}\right]</script><p>and a polynomial equation will be</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">a_nx^n+a_{n-1}x^{n-1}+\cdots+a_1x+a_0 =\left[\begin{array}{c}a_0 \\a_1 \\\cdots \\a_{n-1} \\a_{n} \\0 \\\vdots\end{array}\right]</script><p>and the derivative operative will be</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{d}{dx}=\left[\begin{array}{cccc}0 & 1 & 0 & 0 & \cdots \\0 & 0 & 2 & 0 & \cdots \\0 & 0 & 0 & 3 & \cdots \\0 & 0 & 0 & 0 & \cdots \\\vdots & \vdots & \vdots & \vdots & \vdots\end{array}\right]</script><p>These concepts are correlated:</p><p>Linear transformations and Linear operators; dot products and inner products; eigenvectors and eigenfunctions.</p><h2 id="Rules-for-vectors-addition-and-scaling"><a href="#Rules-for-vectors-addition-and-scaling" class="headerlink" title="Rules for vectors addition and scaling"></a>Rules for vectors addition and scaling</h2><h3 id="Eight-Axioms"><a href="#Eight-Axioms" class="headerlink" title="Eight Axioms"></a>Eight Axioms</h3><h1 id="rule-for-computation"><a href="#rule-for-computation" class="headerlink" title="rule for computation"></a>rule for computation</h1><h2 id="Gaussian-Elimination"><a href="#Gaussian-Elimination" class="headerlink" title="Gaussian Elimination"></a>Gaussian Elimination</h2><h2 id="Cramer’s-rule"><a href="#Cramer’s-rule" class="headerlink" title="Cramer’s rule"></a>Cramer’s rule</h2><h3 id="Orthonormal-Transformation"><a href="#Orthonormal-Transformation" class="headerlink" title="Orthonormal Transformation"></a>Orthonormal Transformation</h3><p>If for all $\vec u$ and $\vec v $, </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">T(\vec u) \cdot T(\vec v) = \vec u \cdot \vec v</script><p>then $T$ is Orthonormal.</p><h3 id="Cramer’s-rule-1"><a href="#Cramer’s-rule-1" class="headerlink" title="Cramer’s rule"></a>Cramer’s rule</h3><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Area} = \text{det}(A)x</script><p>For example,  consider a linear system of equations:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left[\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\0 & 1\end{array}\right]\left[\begin{array}{cc}x \\y\end{array}\right] = \left[\begin{array}{cc}4 \\2\end{array}\right]</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">x = \frac{\left|\begin{array}{cc}4 & -1 \\2 & 1\end{array}\right|}{\left|\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\0 & 1\end{array}\right|}, ~y = \frac{\left|\begin{array}{cc}2 & 4 \\0 & 2\end{array}\right|}{\left|\begin{array}{cc}2 & -1 \\0 & 1\end{array}\right|}</script>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This note contains basic knowledge and summary of Linear Algebra, including vector, matrix, linear transform etc. The main ideas come fro
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Mathematics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/"/>
    
      <category term="Algebra" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Algebra/"/>
    
      <category term="Linear Algebra" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Algebra/Linear-Algebra/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Linear Algebra" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Linear-Algebra/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Optimization Basics</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/22/Applied%20Optimization%20Basics/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/22/Applied Optimization Basics/</id>
    <published>2020-02-22T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-23T21:54:42.746Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This note contains basic knowledge and summary of Optimization, including basic mathematic knowledge etc. The main ideas come from Mooc.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This note contains basic knowledge and summary of Optimization, including basic mathematic knowledge etc. The main ideas come from Mooc.&lt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Mathematics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/"/>
    
      <category term="Applied" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Applied/"/>
    
      <category term="Optimization" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Mathematics/Applied/Optimization/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Optimization" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Optimization/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Asset Pricing - Mathematics</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/21/Summary%20of%20Asset%20Pricing%20Mathematics/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/21/Summary of Asset Pricing Mathematics/</id>
    <published>2020-02-21T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-23T13:19:18.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Stochastic-Processes"><a href="#Stochastic-Processes" class="headerlink" title="Stochastic Processes"></a>Stochastic Processes</h1><h2 id="Regime-switching-affine-processes-with-applications-to-finance"><a href="#Regime-switching-affine-processes-with-applications-to-finance" class="headerlink" title="Regime switching affine processes with applications to finance"></a>Regime switching affine processes with applications to finance</h2><p>21 February 2020 From FS<br><a href="http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00780-020-00419-2?utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00780-020-00419-2?utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound</a><br>We introduce the notion of a <strong>regime switching affine process</strong>. Informally this is a Markov process that behaves conditionally on each regime as an affine process with specific parameters. To facilitate our analysis, specific restrictions are imposed on these parameters. The regime switches are driven by a Markov chain. </p><ul><li>We prove that the joint process of the Markov chain and the conditionally affine part is a process with an affine structure on an enlarged state space, conditionally on the starting state of the Markov chain. </li><li>Like for affine processes, the characteristic function can be expressed in a set of ordinary differential equations that can sometimes be solved analytically. This result unifies several semi-analytical solutions found in the literature for pricing derivatives of specific regime switching processes on smaller state spaces. </li><li>It also provides a unifying theory that allows us to <strong>introduce regime switching to the pricing of many derivatives within the broad class of affine processes</strong>. Examples include European options and term structure derivatives with stochastic volatility and default. </li><li>Essentially, whenever there is a pricing solution based on an affine process, we can extend this to a regime switching affine process without sacrificing the analytical tractability of the affine process.</li></ul><h2 id="The-value-of-informational-arbitrage"><a href="#The-value-of-informational-arbitrage" class="headerlink" title="The value of informational arbitrage"></a>The value of informational arbitrage</h2><p>11 February 2020 from FS<br><a href="http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00780-020-00418-3?utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00780-020-00418-3?utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound</a><br>In the context of a general <strong>semimartingale model</strong>, we aim at determining how much an investor is willing to pay to learn additional information that allows achieving arbitrage. If such a value exists, we call it the value of informational arbitrage. We are interested in the case where the information yields arbitrage opportunities but not unbounded profits with bounded risk. As in Amendinger et al. (Finance Stoch. 7:29–46, 2003), we rely on an indifference valuation approach and study optimal consumption–investment problems under initial information and arbitrage. We establish some new results on models with additional information and characterise when the value of informational arbitrage is universal.</p><h2 id="Semimartingale-theory-of-monotone-mean–variance-portfolio-allocation"><a href="#Semimartingale-theory-of-monotone-mean–variance-portfolio-allocation" class="headerlink" title="Semimartingale theory of monotone mean–variance portfolio allocation"></a>Semimartingale theory of monotone mean–variance portfolio allocation</h2><p>05 March 2020 from MF<br><a href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1903.06912" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://arxiv.org/pdf/1903.06912</a><br>We study dynamic optimal portfolio allocation for monotone mean–variance preferences in a general semimartingale model. Armed with new results in this area, we revisit the work of Cui et al. and <strong>fully characterize the circumstances under which one can set aside a nonnegative cash flow while simultaneously improving the mean–variance efficiency of the left‐over wealth.</strong> The paper analyzes, for the first time, the <strong>monotone hull of the Sharpe ratio</strong> and highlights its relevance to the problem at hand.</p><h2 id="Optimal-equilibria-for-time‐inconsistent-stopping-problems-in-continuous-time"><a href="#Optimal-equilibria-for-time‐inconsistent-stopping-problems-in-continuous-time" class="headerlink" title="Optimal equilibria for time‐inconsistent stopping problems in continuous time"></a>Optimal equilibria for time‐inconsistent stopping problems in continuous time</h2><p>06 March 2020 from MF<br><a href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1712.07806" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://arxiv.org/pdf/1712.07806</a><br>For an infinite‐horizon continuous‐time optimal stopping problem under nonexponential discounting, we look for an optimal equilibrium, which generates larger values than any other equilibrium does on the entire state space. </p><ul><li>When the discount function is log sub‐additive and the state process is one‐dimensional, an optimal equilibrium is constructed in a specific form, under appropriate regularity and integrability conditions. </li><li>Although there may exist other optimal equilibria, we show that they can differ from the constructed one in very limited ways. This leads to a sufficient condition for the uniqueness of optimal equilibria, up to some closedness condition. </li><li>To illustrate our theoretic results, comprehensive analysis is carried out for three specific stopping problems, concerning asset liquidation and real options valuation. For each one of them, an optimal equilibrium is characterized through an explicit formula.</li></ul><h1 id="Hedging-nontradable-risks-with-transaction-costs-and-price-impact"><a href="#Hedging-nontradable-risks-with-transaction-costs-and-price-impact" class="headerlink" title="Hedging nontradable risks with transaction costs and price impact"></a>Hedging nontradable risks with transaction costs and price impact</h1><p>12 March 2020 from MF<br><a href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1908.00054" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://arxiv.org/pdf/1908.00054</a><br>A risk‐averse agent hedges her exposure to a nontradable risk factor U using a correlated traded asset S and accounts for the impact of her trades on both factors. <strong>The effect of the agent’s trades on U is referred to as cross‐impact</strong>. By solving the agent’s stochastic control problem, we obtain a closed‐form expression for <strong>the optimal strategy</strong> when the agent holds a linear position in U. </p><ul><li>When the exposure to the nontradable risk factor is nonlinear, we provide an approximation to <strong>the optimal strategy in closed‐form</strong>, and prove that the value function is correctly approximated by this strategy when cross‐impact and risk‐aversion are small. </li><li>We further prove that when is nonlinear, the approximate optimal strategy can be written <strong>in terms of the optimal strategy for a linear exposure with the size of the position changing dynamically</strong> according to the exposure’s “Delta” under a particular probability measure.</li></ul><h1 id="Utility-Function"><a href="#Utility-Function" class="headerlink" title="Utility Function"></a>Utility Function</h1><h2 id="Consumption-in-incomplete-markets"><a href="#Consumption-in-incomplete-markets" class="headerlink" title="Consumption in incomplete markets"></a>Consumption in incomplete markets</h2><p>09 March 2020 from FS<br><a href="http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00780-020-00420-9?utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00780-020-00420-9?utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound</a><br>We develop a method to find approximate solutions, and their accuracy, to <strong>consumption–investment problems</strong> with isoelastic preferences and infinite horizon, in incomplete markets where <strong>state variables follow a multivariate diffusion</strong>. </p><ul><li>We construct upper and lower contractions; these are fictitious complete markets in which state variables are fully hedgeable, but their dynamics is distorted. Such contractions yield pointwise upper and lower bounds for both the value function and the optimal consumption of the original incomplete market, and their optimal policies are explicit in typical models. Approximate consumption–investment policies coincide with the optimal one if the market is complete or utility is logarithmic.</li></ul><h2 id="Shortfall-aversion"><a href="#Shortfall-aversion" class="headerlink" title="Shortfall aversion"></a>Shortfall aversion</h2><p>05 March 2020 from MF<br><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/mafi.12239?af=R&amp;utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/mafi.12239?af=R&amp;utm_source=researcher_app&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=RESR_MRKT_Researcher_inbound</a><br><strong>Shortfall aversion</strong> reflects the <strong>higher utility loss of spending cuts from a reference</strong> than <strong>the utility gain from similar spending increases</strong>. Inspired by Prospect Theory’s loss aversion and the peak‐end rule, this paper posits a model of utility from <strong>spending scaled by past peak spending</strong>. </p><ul><li>In contrast to traditional models, which call for spending rates proportional to wealth, <strong>the optimal policy in this model</strong> implies <strong>a constant spending rate equal to the historical peak</strong> when wealth is relatively large. The spending rate increases when wealth reaches a model‐determined multiple of peak spending. In 1926–2015, shortfall‐averse spending is smooth and typically increasing.</li></ul><h2 id="Partial-liquidation-under-reference-dependent-preferences"><a href="#Partial-liquidation-under-reference-dependent-preferences" class="headerlink" title="Partial liquidation under reference-dependent preferences"></a>Partial liquidation under reference-dependent preferences</h2><p>16 March 2020 from FS<br><a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007/s00780-020-00421-8.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007/s00780-020-00421-8.pdf</a><br>We propose <strong>a multiple optimal stopping model</strong> where <strong>an investor can sell a divisible asset position at times of her choosing</strong>. </p><ul><li>Investors have -shaped reference-dependent preferences, whereby utility is defined over gains and losses relative to a reference level and is concave over gains and convex over losses. </li><li>For a price process following a time-homogeneous diffusion, we employ the constructive potential-theoretic solution method developed by Dayanik and Karatzas (Stoch. Process. Appl. 107:173–212, 2003). <ul><li>As an example, we revisit the single optimal stopping model of Kyle et al. (J. Econ. Theory 129:273–288, 2006) to allow partial liquidation. </li><li>In contrast to the extant literature, we find that the investor may partially liquidate the asset at distinct price thresholds above the reference level. </li></ul></li><li>Under other parameter combinations, the investor sells the asset in a block, either at or above the reference level.</li></ul><h2 id="Time-Lotteries-and-Stochastic-Impatience"><a href="#Time-Lotteries-and-Stochastic-Impatience" class="headerlink" title="Time Lotteries and Stochastic Impatience"></a>Time Lotteries and Stochastic Impatience</h2><p>20 March 2020 from Econometrica<br><a href="http://eprints.lse.ac.uk/102564/1/TimeLotteries.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://eprints.lse.ac.uk/102564/1/TimeLotteries.pdf</a><br>We study <strong>preferences over lotteries in which both the prize and the payment date are uncertain.</strong> In particular, a time lottery is one in which the prize is fixed but the date is random. </p><ul><li>With Expected Discounted Utility, <strong>individuals must be risk seeking over time lotteries (RSTL)</strong>. In an incentivized experiment, however, we find that almost all subjects violate this property. Our main contributions are theoretical. </li><li>We first show that within a very broad class of models, which includes many forms of nonexpected utility and time discounting, it is impossible to accommodate even a single violation of RSTL without also violating a property we termed Stochastic Impatience, a risky counterpart of standard Impatience. </li><li>We then present two positive results. <ul><li>If one wishes to <strong>maintain Stochastic Impatience</strong>, violations of RSTL can be accommodated by keeping Independence within periods while relaxing it across periods. </li><li>If, instead, one is willing to <strong>forego Stochastic Impatience</strong>, violations of RSTL can be accommodated with a simple generalization of Expected Discounted Utility, obtained by imposing only the behavioral postulates of Discounted Utility and Expected Utility.</li></ul></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h1 id=&quot;Stochastic-Processes&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Stochastic-Processes&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Stochastic Processes&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Stochastic Processes&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Economics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/"/>
    
      <category term="Literature Review" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Literature-Review/"/>
    
      <category term="Asset Pricing" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Literature-Review/Asset-Pricing/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Asset Pricing" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Asset-Pricing/"/>
    
      <category term="Papers" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Papers/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Commodity</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/21/Financial%20Risk%20Management%20Commodity/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/21/Financial Risk Management Commodity/</id>
    <published>2020-02-21T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-13T17:36:19.951Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions.</p><h1 id="Commodity-Overview"><a href="#Commodity-Overview" class="headerlink" title="Commodity Overview"></a>Commodity Overview</h1><h2 id="Commodity-Market"><a href="#Commodity-Market" class="headerlink" title="Commodity Market"></a>Commodity Market</h2><p>Commodities are basic, standardized goods which are traded and used in commerce, often distinguished between “<strong>hard</strong>” (natural resources such as metals and energy) and “<strong>soft</strong>” (crops and livestock) commodities. </p><p>Commodity producers and consumers (both end users and those who use them in production processes) often manage commodity price risk assisted by banks.</p><p><strong>Market dynamics</strong> for individual commodities are unique and specifically linked to the countries, sectors and/or companies which engage in exploration, extraction, refining or production (referred to as producers) and those who use these goods as inputs in production or are end users (known as consumers) and therefore rely on <strong>periodic physical delivery</strong>.</p><p>Producers and consumers often seek to manage exposure to price volatility via standardized future and option contracts traded on commodity exchanges as well as through customized over-the-counter instruments. </p><p>Investors on the other hand with no direct physical exposure have increased commodity investments due to low (and sometimes negative) correlation with other asset types. </p><p>Specific commodities such as gold are sought for wealth preservation and inflation protection by investors seeking a safe haven in volatile markets.</p><h2 id="Participants"><a href="#Participants" class="headerlink" title="Participants"></a>Participants</h2><h3 id="Banks-and-Broker-Dealers"><a href="#Banks-and-Broker-Dealers" class="headerlink" title="Banks and Broker-Dealers"></a>Banks and Broker-Dealers</h3><p>Several large global and U.S. money center banks are engaged in commodity markets, largely as exchange members and OTC derivative and derivatives clearing providers, although some leverage specific credit and industry expertise and client relationships to engage in physical market and structuring opportunities involving financing.</p><h3 id="Exchanges"><a href="#Exchanges" class="headerlink" title="Exchanges"></a>Exchanges</h3><p>Exchanges perform a variety of functions across physical and derivative markets to support producer and consumer activities:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Physical markets</strong> </p><p>require a global network of warehouses to store and deliver on contracts. Exchanges neither own nor operate this network, but create an infrastructure to ensure efficient and secure delivery under physical contract terms. <strong>Investments in commodities generally embed this ongoing cost of storage (“cost of carry”) for a warehoused commodity</strong>. </p></li><li><p><strong>Derivative markets</strong></p><p>are generally designed to mirror physical trading. Similar to other futures and options exchanges, these offer standardized contracts with pre-specified delivery dates, location and underlying commodity specifications. Unlike trading in a financial asset, futures not offset by an opposite sale or purchase prior to settlement date are physically settled.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Example: corn futures</strong></p><p>This Chicago Board of Trade contract specifies 5,000 bushels (~ 127 metric tons) of #2 yellow corn traded in USD with a minimum tick size of $12.50 with contracts expiring each March, May, July, September and December.</p><h2 id="Pricing"><a href="#Pricing" class="headerlink" title="Pricing"></a>Pricing</h2><h3 id="Basis"><a href="#Basis" class="headerlink" title="Basis"></a>Basis</h3><p>Basis is the difference between the cash and futures price for the same commodity:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Basis} = S_0 - F_{0,t}</script><p>where $S_0$ is the current spot price and $F_{0,t}$ is the current futures price for delivery at time t. The basis may be positive or negative at any given time, and as the time to delivery passes, <strong>the futures price will approach the spot price</strong>, resulting in a basis of zero (except for minor differences due to transportation and transaction costs).</p><ul><li><p>Example:</p><p>If the current spot price of gold is $\$1,488.53/t ~ oz$. and the December futures contract is trading at $\$1,499.50/t ~ oz$., the basis equals $-\$10.97$, which is $\$1,488.53 - \$1,499.50$.</p></li></ul><h3 id="Spread"><a href="#Spread" class="headerlink" title="Spread"></a>Spread</h3><p>Spread is the price difference between <strong>futures on the same commodity</strong> for <strong>different maturity dates</strong>:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Spread} = F_{0,t+k} - F_{0,t}</script><p>where $F_{0,t}$ is the current futures price for delivery at t (say in 3 months), while $F_{0,t+k}$ is the current futures price for delivery at $t+k$ (say in 6 months). </p><ul><li><p>Example:</p><p>If the wheat futures contract for delivery in 3 months is $\$3.25$ per bushel, while the 6-month contract is $\$3.30$ per bushel, the spread is $\$0.05$. </p></li></ul><h3 id="Cost-of-Carry-Model"><a href="#Cost-of-Carry-Model" class="headerlink" title="Cost of Carry Model"></a>Cost of Carry Model</h3><p>A simplified way to value a futures contract which assumes futures prices should depend upon the current spot price and the cost of “carrying” or storing (storage, insurance, transportation and financing) the commodity from now until the futures contract matures. </p><p>In its simplest form, it assumes <strong>no transaction costs or margin requirements</strong>, <strong>no restrictions on short selling</strong> and that investors can <strong>freely borrow and lend at the same rate of interest</strong>*:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_{0,t} = S_0(1+C_{0,t})</script><p>Where $C_{0,t}$ is the percentage cost required to store (or “carry”) the commodity from now until time t</p><ul><li><p><strong>Cash and Carry Arbitrage</strong></p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_{0,t} > S_0(1+C_{0,t})</script><p>If the futures contract price exceeds spot plus carry, a trader can borrow, buy the commodity today for cash, sell futures and carry the goods to the futures expiration date. At time t, she delivers the commodity against the futures contract and repays the loan.</p></li><li><p><strong>Reverse Cash and Carry Arbitrage</strong></p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_{0,t} < S_0(1+C_{0,t})</script><p>If the spot price plus carry exceeds the futures price, spot plus carry, the trader can sell short a physical asset. The trader purchases a futures contract, which will be used to honor the short sale commitment. Then the trader lends the proceeds at an established rate of interest. At time t, the trader accepts delivery against the futures contract and uses the commodity received to cover the short position. </p></li></ul><p>Examples:</p><ul><li><p>WTI spot oil is $\$55$ per barrel, and a trader notes annualized carry is $5\%$ or $\$2.75$ for $6$ months. If 6-month WTI futures are $\$60$, how can the trader earn a riskless profit? </p><ul><li>Cash and carry arbitrage - futures are overpriced versus spot plus carry ($\$60 &gt; \$57.75$)</li><li>sell $F_{6mo}$ for $\$60$, </li><li>buy oil now at $\$55$ and </li><li>pay $\$2.75$ carry </li><li>earn $\$2.25$ ($\$60 - \$57.75$) </li></ul></li><li><p>If spot gold is $\$1,450$ /t oz. and the one-year futures contract is at $\$1,460$ with a $3.5\%$ carry cost, how can our trader generate an arbitrage return? </p><ul><li>Reverse cash and carry arbitrage - futures are underpriced versus spot plus carry ($\$1,460 &lt; \$1,500.75$), </li><li>sell gold short in the cash market, </li><li>lend the proceeds </li><li>buy the futures contract </li><li>Take delivery under the futures contract to cover the short gold position and keep $\$40.75$ or $\$1,500.75 - \$1,460$. </li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Spot-and-Futures-relationship"><a href="#Spot-and-Futures-relationship" class="headerlink" title="Spot and Futures relationship"></a>Spot and Futures relationship</h3><ul><li><p><strong>Expectations</strong>: </p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_{0,t}=E{[S_{0,t}]}</script><p>Futures prices are a function of expected spot commodity prices in the future</p></li><li><p><strong>Backwardation</strong>:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_{0,t}<E{[S_{0,t}]}</script><p>suggests <strong>futures markets</strong> are primarily <strong>driven by hedgers with short positions</strong> who pay speculators a premium to assume the price risk. <strong>Speculators take long positions</strong> to assume price risk and are rewarded when futures prices rise to match the spot price at maturity.</p></li><li><p>Contango:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_{0,t}>E[S_{0,t}]</script><p>Suggests that <strong>futures markets</strong> are primarily <strong>driven by hedgers who hold long positions</strong>. For example, grain millers may purchase futures contracts to reduce their price risk. <strong>Hedgers pay speculators a premium to assume the price risk</strong>. Speculators take short positions to assume this price risk and are rewarded when the futures price declines to match the spot price at maturity.</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Commodity-Overview&quot;&gt;&lt;a hr
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Economics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/"/>
    
      <category term="Finance" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/"/>
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/Risk-Management/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Risk-Management/"/>
    
      <category term="NYU" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/NYU/"/>
    
      <category term="FRM" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/FRM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Foreign Exchange</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/14/Financial%20Risk%20Management%20Foreign%20Exchange/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/14/Financial Risk Management Foreign Exchange/</id>
    <published>2020-02-14T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-18T20:20:42.025Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions.</p><h1 id="Foreign-Exchange-Overview"><a href="#Foreign-Exchange-Overview" class="headerlink" title="Foreign Exchange Overview"></a>Foreign Exchange Overview</h1><h2 id="Foreign-Exchange-Market"><a href="#Foreign-Exchange-Market" class="headerlink" title="Foreign Exchange Market"></a>Foreign Exchange Market</h2><p>The global foreign exchange (FX) market represents the highest trading volume of any financial asset class (over $5 trillion daily) and has been historically dominated by large international banks trading in a decentralized, over-the-counter manner in what is referred to as the interbank market.</p><ul><li><p>history: </p><p>Modern-day foreign exchange trading was established in the early 1970s following the breakdown of the post-World War II Bretton Woods monetary agreement and subsequent shift from fixed to floating exchange rates among major global economies</p></li><li><p>purpose:</p><p>The ability to exchange currencies is critical in facilitating the cross-border flow of goods, services and financial assets for transactional and investment purposes.</p></li><li><p>scope:</p><p>total daily FX trading volume exceeded $5 trillion in 2016, is dominated by<br>USD, EUR and JPY spot and FX swap transactions originated in the UK and US.</p></li><li><p>trends:</p><p>FX trading has declined slightly in recent years due to reduced capital and goods flows following the 2008 financial crisis, reduced activity from hedge funds and less appetite among banks to warehouse risk due to increased capital requirements. Emerging fintech-driven non-bank players have increased market share and the proportion of algorithmic trading is rising.</p></li></ul><h3 id="Why-does-the-foreign-exchange-market-have-such-a-size-and-scope"><a href="#Why-does-the-foreign-exchange-market-have-such-a-size-and-scope" class="headerlink" title="Why does the foreign exchange market have such a size and scope"></a>Why does the foreign exchange market have such a size and scope</h3><ul><li>Increasing global interdependence amid growing cross-border financial and goods flows</li><li>Increased wealth and risk appetite drives globalization of investment portfolios</li><li>Continued emerging market growth attracts cross-border capital and goods flows</li></ul><h3 id="Three-primary-foreign-exchange-risk-exposure"><a href="#Three-primary-foreign-exchange-risk-exposure" class="headerlink" title="Three primary foreign exchange risk exposure:"></a>Three primary foreign exchange risk exposure:</h3><ul><li><strong>transaction risk</strong>: the original functional currency value of the transaction will <strong>change or be recorded at a different value</strong></li><li><strong>translation risk</strong>: Firms face the translation of foreign currency denominated balance sheet and income statement items (revenues and expenses) from a foreign currency into its functional currency.</li><li><strong>economic risk</strong>: impact long-term investment decisions</li></ul><h3 id="What-drives-foreign-exchange-rates"><a href="#What-drives-foreign-exchange-rates" class="headerlink" title="What drives foreign exchange rates?"></a>What drives foreign exchange rates?</h3><p>Currency movements are commonly considered as random events more readily explained after the fact than predicted on an ex-ante basis. This would suggest investors are unable to generate alpha while hedgers should only manage FX-based balance sheet and income statement volatility as needed.</p><h2 id="Foreign-Exchange-Rate-Framework"><a href="#Foreign-Exchange-Rate-Framework" class="headerlink" title="Foreign Exchange Rate Framework"></a>Foreign Exchange Rate Framework</h2><h3 id="Monetary-Approach-Purchasing-Power-Parity"><a href="#Monetary-Approach-Purchasing-Power-Parity" class="headerlink" title="Monetary Approach (Purchasing Power Parity)"></a>Monetary Approach (Purchasing Power Parity)</h3><p>Implies an exchange rate should reflect the relative price of the same basket of goods across currencies, or alternatively that the difference in the rate of change in domestic and foreign currency prices (the inflation differential) should equal the percentage depreciation or appreciation of the exchange rate. PPP is too narrow a measure to be used in isolation given the existence of non-standard baskets of goods, non-traded goods and other differences.</p><p>Example:</p><ul><li><p>undervalued:</p><p>A Big Mac costs 130 RUB in Russia and US$5.74 in the U.S. This implies a RUB/USD exchange rate of 22.65. The actual exchange rate of 63.84 RUB/USD suggests the RUB is 64.5% undervalued </p><p>($\frac{63.84 – 22.65}{63.84}$).</p></li><li><p>overvalued:</p><p>A Big Mac costs SFR 6.50 in Switzerland and US$5.74 in the U.S. The implied SFR/USD exchange rate is 1.13. The difference between this and the actual exchange rate of 0.99 SFR/USD suggests the Swiss franc is 14% overvalued </p><p>($\frac{0.99 – 1.13}{0.99}$).</p></li></ul><h3 id="Balance-of-Payments-Approach"><a href="#Balance-of-Payments-Approach" class="headerlink" title="Balance of Payments Approach"></a>Balance of Payments Approach</h3><p>Addresses the implications of trade and capital flows for FX rates, focusing on current (goods, services, dividends and interest) versus capital account (investment, portfolio flows or loans) changes which net to zero. Although in theory any current account imbalances are financed via the capital account, in practice changes to certain components are more material than others, for example commodity-led economies (AUD or BRL) respond more to those flows, while emerging Asia is more impacted by business cycles. Flows matter, but do not explain FX volatility.</p><h3 id="Asset-Markets-Approach"><a href="#Asset-Markets-Approach" class="headerlink" title="Asset Markets Approach"></a>Asset Markets Approach</h3><p>Currencies are highly responsive to current and future fundamentals as embodied in asset prices reflecting the present value of future cash flows denominated in different currencies. Under this explanation, FX prices adjust instantaneously to new information about currency fundamentals. This approach is supported by strong empirical evidence and forms the basis for trading.</p><h3 id="Central-bank-FX-market-intervention"><a href="#Central-bank-FX-market-intervention" class="headerlink" title="Central bank FX market intervention"></a>Central bank FX market intervention</h3><p>This is an additional overlay, particularly in emerging markets driven by an aim to either address an imbalance, offset volatility or accumulate FX reserves.</p><h1 id="Foreign-Exchange-Convention"><a href="#Foreign-Exchange-Convention" class="headerlink" title="Foreign Exchange Convention"></a>Foreign Exchange Convention</h1><h2 id="Inverse-and-direct-quoting"><a href="#Inverse-and-direct-quoting" class="headerlink" title="Inverse and direct quoting"></a>Inverse and direct quoting</h2><h3 id="Inverse-quotes"><a href="#Inverse-quotes" class="headerlink" title="Inverse quotes"></a>Inverse quotes</h3><p>Several major (and a few minor) currencies are quoted as <strong>the number of U.S. dollars required to purchase one unit of currency</strong>.</p><ul><li><p>EUR / USD = 1.11</p><ul><li><strong>Therefore a stronger EUR will result in a higher EUR/USD</strong>, similar to a stock</li></ul></li><li><p>GBP / USD</p></li><li><p>AUD / USD</p></li><li><p>NZD / USD</p></li></ul><h3 id="Direct-quotes"><a href="#Direct-quotes" class="headerlink" title="Direct quotes"></a>Direct quotes</h3><p>For all other currencies, <strong>prices are quoted as the number of units of foreign currency which buys one US dollar</strong></p><ul><li>USD / JPY = 107.8<ul><li>This figure rises as JPY weakens and the USD strengthens</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Foreign-Exchange-Tools"><a href="#Foreign-Exchange-Tools" class="headerlink" title="Foreign Exchange Tools"></a>Foreign Exchange Tools</h1><h2 id="Spot-and-Forward"><a href="#Spot-and-Forward" class="headerlink" title="Spot and Forward"></a>Spot and Forward</h2><h3 id="Spot"><a href="#Spot" class="headerlink" title="Spot"></a>Spot</h3><h4 id="Spot-FX-mechanics"><a href="#Spot-FX-mechanics" class="headerlink" title="Spot FX mechanics"></a>Spot FX mechanics</h4><p>Spot transactions are cash transactions usually settled on <strong>the second business<br>day (T+2) after the trade date</strong> (CAD, TRY, MXN and RUB settle next day) under an agreement between two parties (one of whom is often a bank) to purchase or sell units of a base currency.</p><ul><li><p>Example:</p><p>A EUR/USD quote of 1.1526 [1.15 representing the ‘big figure’, and the 26 expressed as ‘pips’) means a counterparty purchases one EUR in exchange for $1.1526 dollars. </p></li><li><p>Spot trade exposure is referred to as <strong>settlement risk</strong>, which arises <strong>when one party transfers funds in one currency in anticipation of receiving payment in another currency from another party</strong>.</p></li><li><p>Spot comprises less than half of overall FX volume, as market participants usually manage forecasted transaction risks using FX derivatives.</p></li></ul><h3 id="Forward"><a href="#Forward" class="headerlink" title="Forward"></a>Forward</h3><p>These involve the exchange of one currency for another at a pre-agreed rate on a pre-determined date ranging from T+3 to several weeks or years. This is the formula:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F = S_0 \frac{(1+y_{US})^T}{(1+y_{FC})^T}</script><p>In continuous time:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">F_t = S_0e^{(r-r_f)t}</script><ul><li><p>Example:</p><p>Assume the spot EUR/USD FX rate is 1.10 (i.e., US$ 1.10 buys one euro). If the EUR one  year benchmark rate is -0.4% and an equivalent USD one-year benchmark is 2.00%, solve for the one year EUR / USD forward rate.</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">1.10 \times\frac{1+0.02}{1-0.004}=1.1265</script><p>Note that the higher the interest rate in USD in this case, the more expensive it is to purchase EUR in one year’s time given that the buyer foregoes one year of the higher USD interest.</p></li></ul><h4 id="Forward-Contract-mechanics"><a href="#Forward-Contract-mechanics" class="headerlink" title="Forward Contract mechanics"></a>Forward Contract mechanics</h4><p>Foreign exchange forward transactions are quoted in ‘<strong>points</strong>’, or the (positive or negative) <strong>difference in the forward and spot quote</strong> scaled to the last decimal in the corresponding spot quote.</p><ul><li><p>Example: </p><p>the one-year forward rate of +265 points would apply to EUR/USD in our above example, the corresponding forward rate being 1.10 + (265/10,000) = 1.1265. Many firms <strong>hedge transaction exposure for relatively certain forecasted transactions</strong> such as <strong>accounts receivable</strong> or <strong>payable</strong> as well as investment exposures using currency forward transactions.</p></li></ul><h2 id="Non-deliverable-FX-forwards-swaps-and-options"><a href="#Non-deliverable-FX-forwards-swaps-and-options" class="headerlink" title="Non-deliverable FX forwards, swaps and options"></a>Non-deliverable FX forwards, swaps and options</h2><ul><li><p>Exchange Rate Restrictions </p><p>Although freely floating currencies are predominant among major industrial nations, only around 30 global currencies are freely floating, with others (mostly emerging markets (EM) currencies) subject to controls such as restrictions on trading or exchanging currencies.</p></li></ul><h3 id="Non-Deliverable-FX-Forwards-NDFs"><a href="#Non-Deliverable-FX-Forwards-NDFs" class="headerlink" title="Non-Deliverable FX Forwards (NDFs)"></a>Non-Deliverable FX Forwards (NDFs)</h3><p>These are similar to standard forward agreements in that they involve the exchange of one currency’s value for another at a pre-agreed rate on a pre-determined date. However, <strong>given onshore currency restrictions</strong>, they are settled in <strong>a convertible currency (usually USD) offshore without a physical exchange of the hedged currency</strong>.</p><ul><li><p>Example:</p><p>A corporation enters into a $1 million NDF to purchase BRL and sell USD for settlement in one month at a forward rate of 3.79 BRL/USD. </p><ul><li>In one month, the NDF breaks even if USD 1,000,000 = BRL 3,790,000. </li><li>If BRL strengthens to 3.70 instead, the BRL buyer has a gain of BRL 90,000 on the fixing date. <ul><li>The NDF contract is settled offshore for USD 24,324 (= BRL 90,000 / 3.70).</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Forward versus NDF pricing</strong></p><p>While interest rate parity helps explain forward pricing, it is generally less the case for NDFs, which may diverge due to <strong>expected FX regime change</strong>, <strong>speculative positioning</strong>, capital flows, local onshore rate markets and the relationship between offshore and onshore currency forward markets. </p><p>If international investors <strong>cannot access onshore rate markets or deposits in local currency</strong>, NDF prices for the currency are based primarily on <strong>the expected future spot exchange rate</strong>.</p></li></ul><h2 id="FX-Swaps"><a href="#FX-Swaps" class="headerlink" title="FX Swaps"></a>FX Swaps</h2><p>Combines offsetting and simultaneously executed FX spot and forward transactions. In an FX swap, the base currency is purchased (or sold) on a spot basis and sold (or purchased) on a forward basis. </p><ul><li>These are distinct from cross-currency interest rate swaps which involve intermediate cash flows to transform a fixed-income exposure from one currency to another (addressed later). </li><li>A primary use for FX swaps is to replace or “roll” forward transactions as they approach maturity.</li></ul><h2 id="FX-Options"><a href="#FX-Options" class="headerlink" title="FX Options"></a>FX Options</h2><p>Like options in other asset classes, option transactions involve the purchase or sale of the right, but not the obligation to exchange one currency for another at a pre-determined “strike” price on a pre-determined date in the future. </p><ul><li>Many firms hedge the exposure they face for uncertain forecasted transactions in other currencies using options.</li></ul><h2 id="Cross-currency-swaps"><a href="#Cross-currency-swaps" class="headerlink" title="Cross-currency swaps"></a>Cross-currency swaps</h2><h3 id="cross-currency-swaps"><a href="#cross-currency-swaps" class="headerlink" title="cross-currency swaps"></a>cross-currency swaps</h3><p><strong>A series of FX forwards</strong> designed to <strong>convert recurring or periodic cash flows from one currency to another</strong>, or effectively the <strong>exchange of a floating rate note in one currency with that of another</strong>.</p><ul><li><p>Example of a JPY investor buying a USD bond:</p><p>| Time | Action                                                       |<br>| —— | —————————————————————————————— |<br>| T=0  | Investor must sell JPY, buy USD at spot to pay for USD bond  |<br>| T=t  | Investor receives USD coupons and must convert at unknown future JPY/USD spot rate |<br>| T=n  | Investor receives final USD coupon and principal and must convert back to JPY at unknown future JPY/USD spot rate |</p></li></ul><h3 id="floating-floating-cross-currency-basis-swap"><a href="#floating-floating-cross-currency-basis-swap" class="headerlink" title="floating-floating cross-currency basis swap"></a>floating-floating cross-currency basis swap</h3><p>involve both initial and final exchange of principal upon inception and maturity at the current spot rate, with a periodic exchange of floating benchmark rates.</p><h3 id="Use-of-cross-currency-swaps"><a href="#Use-of-cross-currency-swaps" class="headerlink" title="Use of cross-currency swaps"></a>Use of cross-currency swaps</h3><ul><li><p>common among investors seeking bringing offshore investments back to their home currency and issuers hedging translation risk or foreign currency debt issuance.</p></li><li><p>Pricing and Interest Rate Parity</p><ul><li>Classical interest rate parity requires that currencies may be invested at risk-free zero-coupon rates, a condition which is not satisfied by instruments based upon swap rates</li></ul></li><li><p>Classical interest rate parity requires that currencies may be invested at risk-free zero-coupon rates, a condition which is not satisfied by instruments based upon swap rates</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Foreign-Exchange-Overview
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Economics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/"/>
    
      <category term="Finance" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/"/>
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/Risk-Management/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Risk-Management/"/>
    
      <category term="NYU" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/NYU/"/>
    
      <category term="FRM" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/FRM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Economic Inequality Papers</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/10/Summary%20of%20Economic%20Inequality%20Papers/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/10/Summary of Economic Inequality Papers/</id>
    <published>2020-02-10T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-01T01:42:35.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Heterogeneity-and-Persistence-in-Returns-to-Wealth"><a href="#Heterogeneity-and-Persistence-in-Returns-to-Wealth" class="headerlink" title="Heterogeneity and Persistence in Returns to Wealth"></a>Heterogeneity and Persistence in Returns to Wealth</h2><p>July 2018<br><a href="https://www.imf.org/~/media/Files/Publications/WP/2018/wp18171.ashx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.imf.org/~/media/Files/Publications/WP/2018/wp18171.ashx</a><br>We provide a systematic <strong>analysis of the properties of individual returns to wealth</strong> using 12 years of population data from Norway’s administrative tax records. We document a number of novel results. </p><ul><li>First, individuals earn markedly different average returns on their net worth (a standard deviation of 22.1%) and on its components. </li><li>Second, heterogeneity in returns does not arise merely from differences in the allocation of wealth between safe and risky assets: <strong>returns are heterogeneous even within narrow asset classes</strong>. </li><li>Third, returns are positively correlated with wealth: moving from the 10th to the 90th percentile of the net worth distribution increases the return by 18 percentage points (and 10 percentage points if looking at net‐of‐tax returns). </li><li>Fourth, individual wealth returns exhibit substantial persistence over time. We argue that while this persistence partly arises from stable differences in risk exposure and assets scale, it also reflects heterogeneity in sophistication and financial information, as well as entrepreneurial talent. </li><li>Finally, <strong>wealth returns are correlated across generations</strong>. We discuss the implications of these findings for several strands of the wealth inequality debate.</li></ul><h2 id="Genetic-Endowments-and-Wealth-Inequality"><a href="#Genetic-Endowments-and-Wealth-Inequality" class="headerlink" title="Genetic Endowments and Wealth Inequality"></a>Genetic Endowments and Wealth Inequality</h2><p>29 Feb 2020 from JPE<br><a href="http://www.nber.org/papers/w24642.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">http://www.nber.org/papers/w24642.pdf</a><br>We show that <strong>genetic endowments</strong> linked to <strong>educational attainment</strong> strongly and robustly predict <strong>wealth at retirement</strong>. The estimated relationship is not fully explained by flexibly controlling for education and labor income. </p><ul><li>We therefore investigate a host of additional mechanisms that could account for the gene-wealth gradient, including inheritances, mortality, risk preferences, portfolio decisions, beliefs about the probabilities of macroeconomic events, and planning horizons. </li><li>We provide evidence that genetic endowments related to <strong>human capital accumulation</strong> are associated with wealth not only through <strong>educational attainment and labor income</strong> but also through <strong>a facility with complex financial decision-making</strong>.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h2 id=&quot;Heterogeneity-and-Persistence-in-Returns-to-Wealth&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Heterogeneity-and-Persistence-in-Returns-to-Wealth&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot;
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Economics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/"/>
    
      <category term="Literature Review" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Literature-Review/"/>
    
      <category term="Inequality" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Literature-Review/Inequality/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Papers" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Papers/"/>
    
      <category term="Inequality" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Inequality/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Machine Learning Overview</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/08/ML%20Overview/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/08/ML Overview/</id>
    <published>2020-02-08T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-17T14:39:07.918Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This notes is based on the class Machine Learning in Finance of NYU MFE, including basic knowledge of supervised learning.</p><h1 id="Supervised-Learning"><a href="#Supervised-Learning" class="headerlink" title="Supervised Learning"></a>Supervised Learning</h1><h2 id="Definition"><a href="#Definition" class="headerlink" title="Definition"></a>Definition</h2><p>The goal is to use the inputs to predict the values of the outputs. This exercise is called supervised learning.</p><h2 id="variables"><a href="#variables" class="headerlink" title="variables"></a>variables</h2><p>inputs: predictors, independent variables,which are measured or preset.</p><p>output: responses, dependent variables</p><h3 id="variable-types"><a href="#variable-types" class="headerlink" title="variable types"></a>variable types</h3><ul><li>quantitative / continuous variables</li><li><p>categorical / discrete variables / factors /</p><ul><li>qualitative</li><li>dummy variables </li></ul></li><li><p>ordered categorical</p></li></ul><h2 id="Algorithm"><a href="#Algorithm" class="headerlink" title="Algorithm"></a>Algorithm</h2><h3 id="k-Nearest-Neighbors"><a href="#k-Nearest-Neighbors" class="headerlink" title="k-Nearest Neighbors"></a>k-Nearest Neighbors</h3><h3 id="Linear-Regression"><a href="#Linear-Regression" class="headerlink" title="Linear Regression"></a>Linear Regression</h3><h3 id="Logistic-Regression"><a href="#Logistic-Regression" class="headerlink" title="Logistic Regression"></a>Logistic Regression</h3><h3 id="Support-Vector-Machines"><a href="#Support-Vector-Machines" class="headerlink" title="Support Vector Machines"></a>Support Vector Machines</h3><h3 id="Decision-Trees-and-Random-Forests"><a href="#Decision-Trees-and-Random-Forests" class="headerlink" title="Decision Trees and Random Forests"></a>Decision Trees and Random Forests</h3><h3 id="Neural-Networks"><a href="#Neural-Networks" class="headerlink" title="Neural Networks"></a>Neural Networks</h3><h1 id="Unsupervised-Learning"><a href="#Unsupervised-Learning" class="headerlink" title="Unsupervised Learning"></a>Unsupervised Learning</h1><h2 id="Algorithm-1"><a href="#Algorithm-1" class="headerlink" title="Algorithm"></a>Algorithm</h2><h3 id="k-means"><a href="#k-means" class="headerlink" title="k-means"></a>k-means</h3><h3 id="Hierarchical-Cluster-Analysis"><a href="#Hierarchical-Cluster-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="Hierarchical Cluster Analysis"></a>Hierarchical Cluster Analysis</h3><h3 id="Expectation-Maximization"><a href="#Expectation-Maximization" class="headerlink" title="Expectation Maximization"></a>Expectation Maximization</h3><h3 id="Principal-Component-Analysis"><a href="#Principal-Component-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="Principal Component Analysis"></a>Principal Component Analysis</h3><h3 id="Locally-Linear-Embedding"><a href="#Locally-Linear-Embedding" class="headerlink" title="Locally-Linear Embedding"></a>Locally-Linear Embedding</h3><h3 id="t-distributed-Stochastic-Neighbor-Embedding"><a href="#t-distributed-Stochastic-Neighbor-Embedding" class="headerlink" title="t-distributed Stochastic Neighbor Embedding"></a>t-distributed Stochastic Neighbor Embedding</h3><h1 id="Steps-for-a-ML-project"><a href="#Steps-for-a-ML-project" class="headerlink" title="Steps for a ML project"></a>Steps for a ML project</h1><h2 id="Overview"><a href="#Overview" class="headerlink" title="Overview"></a>Overview</h2><h3 id="Frame-the-problem"><a href="#Frame-the-problem" class="headerlink" title="Frame the problem"></a>Frame the problem</h3><h3 id="Data-Understanding"><a href="#Data-Understanding" class="headerlink" title="Data Understanding"></a>Data Understanding</h3><ul><li>descriptive statistics</li><li>relationship between independent and dependent variables (graphs)</li></ul><h3 id="Data-Cleaning"><a href="#Data-Cleaning" class="headerlink" title="Data Cleaning"></a>Data Cleaning</h3><ul><li><p>missing values</p><ul><li>filling: filling n.a.</li><li>delete: drop n.a.</li></ul></li><li><p>feature engineering</p><ul><li>abstract feature </li><li>select feature </li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Machine-Learning-Model"><a href="#Machine-Learning-Model" class="headerlink" title="Machine Learning Model"></a>Machine Learning Model</h3><ul><li>split training and testing</li><li>algorithm</li></ul><h3 id="Evaluate-Model"><a href="#Evaluate-Model" class="headerlink" title="Evaluate Model"></a>Evaluate Model</h3><ul><li>score</li><li>cross validation</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This notes is based on the class Machine Learning in Finance of NYU MFE, including basic knowledge of supervised learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Su
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Computer Science" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/"/>
    
      <category term="Machine Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Computer-Science/Machine-Learning/"/>
    
    
      <category term="NYU" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/NYU/"/>
    
      <category term="Machine Learning" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Machine-Learning/"/>
    
      <category term="Artificial Intelligence" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Artificial-Intelligence/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Fixed Income</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2020/02/07/Financial%20Risk%20Management%20Fixed%20Income/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2020/02/07/Financial Risk Management Fixed Income/</id>
    <published>2020-02-07T05:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-13T17:36:48.613Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions of Fixed Income.</p><h1 id="Fixed-Income-Overview"><a href="#Fixed-Income-Overview" class="headerlink" title="Fixed Income Overview"></a>Fixed Income Overview</h1><h2 id="Fixed-Income-Market"><a href="#Fixed-Income-Market" class="headerlink" title="Fixed Income Market"></a>Fixed Income Market</h2><ul><li>identify primary risks</li><li>classify other risks which are incidental to the business</li><li>maximize return for a given level of risk</li></ul><h2 id="Compared-to-Equity-Market"><a href="#Compared-to-Equity-Market" class="headerlink" title="Compared to Equity Market"></a>Compared to Equity Market</h2><h3 id="Why-equity-is-special"><a href="#Why-equity-is-special" class="headerlink" title="Why equity is special?"></a>Why equity is special?</h3><ul><li>equity market is with much more volatility<ul><li>because the residuals take over the leftovers and risks of bankruptcy</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Why-Debt-market-size-is-larger-than-equity-market"><a href="#Why-Debt-market-size-is-larger-than-equity-market" class="headerlink" title="Why Debt market size is larger than equity market?"></a>Why Debt market size is larger than equity market?</h3><ul><li>Indebtedness outside of the Private Sector</li><li><strong>Cost and Other Benefits of Debt Financing</strong> and Leverage<ul><li>loans / debt financing is cheaper than equity</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Why-in-emerging-market-debt-market-and-equity-market-is-inverse"><a href="#Why-in-emerging-market-debt-market-and-equity-market-is-inverse" class="headerlink" title="Why in emerging market, debt market and equity market is inverse?"></a>Why in emerging market, debt market and equity market is inverse?</h3><ul><li>emerging market is more likely to grow</li><li>then there is more volatility </li><li>more currency to rush in</li></ul><h3 id="Advantage-of-Fixed-Income"><a href="#Advantage-of-Fixed-Income" class="headerlink" title="Advantage of Fixed Income"></a>Advantage of Fixed Income</h3><ul><li>Time Value of Money Cost of Carry</li><li>Key Instrument of Monetary Policy</li><li>Discounting Tool for All Other Asset Classes and Investments</li><li><p>Key Factor in the Balance Sheet of Financial Firms</p></li><li><p>for lenders: give your money back</p></li></ul><h1 id="Bond-Pricing"><a href="#Bond-Pricing" class="headerlink" title="Bond Pricing"></a>Bond Pricing</h1><h2 id="Value-of-Bond"><a href="#Value-of-Bond" class="headerlink" title="Value of Bond"></a>Value of Bond</h2><p>Price of a bond is the present value (PV) of the promised cash flows</p><ul><li><p>Promised cash flows are <strong>coupons</strong> and repayment of <strong>principal</strong> at maturity</p></li><li><p>Coupon payments are on regularly scheduled dates</p></li></ul><p>Market discount = yield</p><p>Valuation basics:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">PV = \frac{PMT}{(1+r)^1}+\frac{PMT}{(1+r)^2}+...+\frac{PMT+FV}{(1+r)^N}</script><p>If $PMT &lt; r$, priced at a discount below par.</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">94.583 = \frac{2}{(1+3\%)^1}+\frac{2}{(1+3\%)^2}+\frac{2}{(1+3\%)^3}+\frac{2}{(1+3\%)^4}+\frac{2}{(1+3\%)^5}+\frac{102}{(1+3\%)^6}</script><p>If $PMT &gt; r$, priced at a premium above par.</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">107.26 = \frac{6}{(1+4\%)^1}+\frac{6}{(1+4\%)^2}+\frac{6}{(1+4\%)^3}+\frac{106}{(1+4\%)^4}</script><p>If $PMT = r$, priced at par</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">100 = \frac{3}{(1+3\%)^1}+\frac{3}{(1+3\%)^2}+\frac{3}{(1+3\%)^3}+\frac{3}{(1+3\%)^4}+\frac{103}{(1+3\%)^5}</script><h2 id="Yield-to-Maturity"><a href="#Yield-to-Maturity" class="headerlink" title="Yield to Maturity"></a>Yield to Maturity</h2><h3 id="Three-conditions"><a href="#Three-conditions" class="headerlink" title="Three conditions"></a>Three conditions</h3><ul><li>Holds the bond to maturity</li><li>Receives all coupon and principal payments (no default)</li><li>May <strong>reinvest all coupon payments at the same yield</strong> (hard  to be realistic)</li></ul><h3 id="Relationship-between-bond-price-and-YTM"><a href="#Relationship-between-bond-price-and-YTM" class="headerlink" title="Relationship between bond price and YTM"></a>Relationship between bond price and YTM</h3><ul><li>Inverse Effect: Duration</li><li>Convexity Effect: convexity</li><li>Coupon Effect</li><li>Maturity Effect: prices of a bond converge to par</li></ul><h2 id="Quotes-and-Conventions"><a href="#Quotes-and-Conventions" class="headerlink" title="Quotes and Conventions"></a>Quotes and Conventions</h2><h3 id="Full-Price-and-Flat-Price"><a href="#Full-Price-and-Flat-Price" class="headerlink" title="Full Price and Flat Price"></a>Full Price and Flat Price</h3><p>Relation:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Full (“Dirty”) Price} = \text{Flat (“Clean”) Price} + \text{Accrued Interest}</script><ul><li><p>Dealers <strong>quote</strong> clean prices but <strong>settle</strong> at the dirty price.</p></li><li><p>accrued interest</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Accrued Interest} = \frac{t}{T} \times PMT</script><p>where t is days from last coupon date to settlement and T is days in coupon period</p><p>Days conventions:</p><ul><li>U.S. Treasury notes, bonds (2 - 30 years): Semiannual, Actual / Actual basis</li><li>U.S. corporate bonds: Semiannual, 30/360 basis</li><li>European government and corporate bonds: Annual, Actual/Actual basis</li></ul></li></ul><p>Examples: </p><ul><li><p>A U.S. T bond with 5/15 and 11/15 coupon dates trades with settlement on 6/27. Calculate accrued interest based upon a 5% coupon:</p><p>Actual days from 5/15 to 6/27 is 43, Actual days from 5/15 to 11/15 is 184.</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">AI = \frac{43}{184}\times\frac{5.00}{2} = 0.584239 ~~\text{per \$100 of par}</script></li></ul><h3 id="Discount-basis-or-Add-on-basis"><a href="#Discount-basis-or-Add-on-basis" class="headerlink" title="Discount basis or Add-on basis"></a>Discount basis or Add-on basis</h3><p>Money market instruments are short term $(&lt; 1 ~ \text{year})$ securities with annualized (not compounded) return measures quoted on a <strong>discount</strong> or <strong>add on</strong> basis</p><ul><li>DR: U S commercial paper, Treasury bills and bankers’ acceptances</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">PV = FV \times (1-\frac{Days}{Year}\times DR)</script><ul><li>AOR: Bank certificates of deposit (CDs), repurchase agreements and LIBOR / EURIBOR</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">PV = \frac{FV}{(1+\frac{Days}{Year}\times AOR)}</script><p>Example:</p><ul><li><p>DR understates investor return / cost of borrowed funds as it divides by the total return at FV versus PV. For example, for a 90 day, $10 MM instrument:</p><ul><li><p>T-bill @ DR of 2.25%</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}PV &=& FV \times (1-\frac{Days}{Year}\times DR) \\&=& 10 \times (1-\frac{90}{360}\times 0.0225) \\&=& 9943750\end{eqnarray*}</script></li><li><p>Bank CD @ AOR of 2.25%</p></li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}PV &=& \frac{FV}{(1+\frac{Days}{Year}\times AOR)} \\&=& \frac{10}{(1+\frac{90}{360}\times 0.0225)} \\&=& 9944065\end{eqnarray*}</script></li></ul><h3 id="Periodicity-conversion"><a href="#Periodicity-conversion" class="headerlink" title="Periodicity conversion"></a>Periodicity conversion</h3><p>from m to n periods (i.e., from monthly to quarterly):</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\left(1 + \frac{APR_m}{m} \right)^{m} = \left(1 + \frac{APR_n}{n} \right)^{n}</script><h3 id="Semiannual-Bond-Equivalent-Yield"><a href="#Semiannual-Bond-Equivalent-Yield" class="headerlink" title="Semiannual Bond Equivalent Yield"></a>Semiannual Bond Equivalent Yield</h3><p>Most common periodicity for USD denominated bond yields is two. An annual rate having a periodicity of two is known as a semiannual bond basis yield, or semiannual bond equivalent yield.<br>Example: </p><ul><li>What is the SA bond equivalent for a zero priced at 78 2 maturing in 4 years?<script type="math/tex; mode=display">78.2 = \frac{100}{(1+r)^8} \\r = 0.0167</script>Semiannual yield = 0.0334 </li></ul><h2 id="Matrix-Pricing"><a href="#Matrix-Pricing" class="headerlink" title="Matrix Pricing"></a>Matrix Pricing</h2><p>to price a new issued bond</p><h3 id="Principle-of-Matrix-Pricing"><a href="#Principle-of-Matrix-Pricing" class="headerlink" title="Principle of Matrix Pricing"></a>Principle of Matrix Pricing</h3><p>Suppose a BBB rated pharmaceutical corporation intends to <strong>issue a new five year bond</strong>. The firm currently has a four year, 4 annual coupon bond outstanding which is priced at 103.1 (full and flat price with accrued interest of zero) The <strong>four year rate of return rate</strong> required by investors is 3.16%:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">103.1 = \frac{4}{(1+r\%)^1}+\frac{4}{(1+r\%)^2}+\frac{4}{(1+r\%)^3}+\frac{104}{(1+r\%)^4}, ~r = 3.16\%</script><p>Without a four year government bond to calculate a more precise yield spread, we look to three year<br>and five year ‘on the run’ government bonds yielding 2.10 and 2.45 respectively. The average of<br>the two yields is 2.2750%, which is the estimated four year benchmark yield.</p><p>The <strong>estimated yield spread</strong> is 88.5 bps over the implied benchmark rate $(0.0316-0.02275 =0.00885)$. </p><p>The issuer and underwriter then compare and adjust this four year yield spread based upon recent five year issues for companies <strong>with similar ratings</strong> and/or in <strong>the same industry</strong> for a proposed spread for the new issuance.</p><h3 id="Credit-spreads"><a href="#Credit-spreads" class="headerlink" title="Credit spreads"></a>Credit spreads</h3><ul><li><strong>Benchmark spread</strong> is the spread over the most recently issued government bond of similar maturity</li><li><strong>G-spread</strong> is the spread over actual or interpolated government bond with matched maturity</li><li><strong>I-spread</strong> is the spread over swap rates that match the credit security’s tenor and currency</li><li><strong>Z-spread</strong> is the zero volatility spread measured across each point along the implied spot yield curve</li><li><strong>Option adjusted spread (OAS)</strong> is a generalized Z spread and often most appropriate for portfolios</li></ul><h3 id="Current-yield"><a href="#Current-yield" class="headerlink" title="Current yield"></a>Current yield</h3><p>Current yield is sometimes called the <strong>income or interest yield</strong> and is the <strong>sum of coupon payments<br>received</strong> over the year divided by the <strong>flat price</strong>.</p><p>For example, a 10 year, 2 semiannual coupon payment bond is priced at 95 per 100 of par value Its current yield is $\frac{2}{95} = 2.105%$. This crude measure neglects coupon payment frequency in the numerator and accrued interest in the denominator</p><h1 id="Structure-of-Interest-rates"><a href="#Structure-of-Interest-rates" class="headerlink" title="Structure of Interest rates"></a>Structure of Interest rates</h1><h2 id="yield-curve"><a href="#yield-curve" class="headerlink" title="yield curve"></a>yield curve</h2><h3 id="definition"><a href="#definition" class="headerlink" title="definition"></a>definition</h3><p>The yield curve on coupon bonds is a snapshot of rates for non-callable securities with similar risk profile across maturities.</p><ul><li>Yield curves generally have <strong>a positive slope</strong> given the <strong>higher risk of holding longer-term securities</strong><ul><li>Investors typically demand a higher premium to lend for longer</li><li>The change in price for a given change in yield is higher for longer duration securities</li></ul></li><li><p>Yield curve shape is dynamic, and the term structure is influenced by various factors</p><ul><li>Short-term policy rates such as U.S. Federal Funds tend to drive short-term yields</li><li>Long-term Treasury yields are more affected by long-term inflation and growth expectations</li><li>U.S. Federal Funds have an impact on long-term yield by adjusting short-term yields</li></ul></li><li><p>Term structure theories are driven by <strong>expectations</strong>, <strong>segmentation</strong> and <strong>liquidity preference</strong></p><ul><li>Expectations theories rely solely on investor / issuer expectations of future short-term rates</li><li>Segmented market theory implies that investors / issuers have limited maturity selection</li><li>Liquidity preference theory combines risk and return as critical factors for issuers / investors</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="shapes-tool-to-forecast-economic-activity"><a href="#shapes-tool-to-forecast-economic-activity" class="headerlink" title="shapes - tool to forecast economic activity"></a>shapes - tool to forecast economic activity</h3><ul><li><p>A positively sloped curve is generally associated with a future increase in real economic activity</p></li><li><p><strong>Curve flattening or inversion</strong> where short term yields exceed long term yields portends <strong>a drop in short term rates and an expected decline in GDP</strong></p></li></ul><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/02/11/t1LvP57m3b2GwrM.png" alt="yield_curve_invision.png"></p><p>Influence Factors:</p><ul><li>Monetary policy (<strong>tightening tends to slow the economy and flatten (or invert) the curve</strong>) </li><li>Investor expectations of future short-term rates as influenced by both credit demand and expected inflation </li><li>General financial market conditions</li></ul><h3 id="spot-curves"><a href="#spot-curves" class="headerlink" title="spot curves"></a>spot curves</h3><p>Zero curves represent one cash flow on a pre-determined date. </p><ul><li>One example is for zero-coupon government bonds across maturities. This government bond spot curve (or zero or “strip” curve as individual coupons are “stripped” off of coupon bonds) is a set of yields-to-maturity on zero-coupon bonds. While often referred to as “risk-free” yields, this only refers to relative default risk, not inflation or liquidity risk.</li></ul><h3 id="par-curves"><a href="#par-curves" class="headerlink" title="par curves"></a>par curves</h3><p>Par curves represent par value bonds maturing on pre-determined dates. </p><ul><li>In addition to the yield curve on coupon bonds and the spot curve on zero-coupon bonds, maturity structure can be assessed using a par curve. A par curve is <strong>a sequence of yields-to-maturity such that each bond is priced at par value</strong>. The bonds have the same currency, credit risk, liquidity, tax status, and annual yields stated for the same periodicity</li></ul><h3 id="forward-curves"><a href="#forward-curves" class="headerlink" title="forward curves"></a>forward curves</h3><p>Forward curves are a series of forward (future delivery) rates derived from spot rates. </p><ul><li>Implied forward rates (also known as forward yields) are calculated from spot rates as a break-even reinvestment rate linking return on investment in a shorter-term zero-coupon bond to that of a longer-term zero-coupon bond.</li></ul><p>Example:</p><p>There are two alternative loans:</p><ul><li>A is for 1 year at 2%; B is for 2 Years at 3%. Then $F_{1,1}$ is the one-year rate a year from now which equates 102 at year 1 to 106 at year 2:<script type="math/tex; mode=display">r = \frac{106}{102}-1 = 3.9216\%</script>which means <script type="math/tex; mode=display">102 \times 1.039216 = 106</script>The implied forward rate may be checked by investing 102 for 1 year at this rate. This is also the basic principle of forward rate agreement(FRA):<script type="math/tex; mode=display">(1 + Z_A)^A \times(1+IFR_{A,B-A})^{B-A}=(1+Z_B)^B</script>A is the shorter term bond in A periods. B is longer term bond in B periods.</li></ul><h1 id="Source-of-bond-risk"><a href="#Source-of-bond-risk" class="headerlink" title="Source of bond risk"></a>Source of bond risk</h1><p>The market value sensitivity of a bond (or other rate sensitive instrument) to interest rate changes is<br>based on the bond valuation formula shown below based upon the full (or “dirty”) price</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">MV = \frac{PMT}{(1+y)^{1-\frac{t}{T}}} + \frac{PMT}{(1+y)^{2-\frac{t}{T}}}+ ... +\frac{PMT}{(1+y)^{N-\frac{t}{T}}}</script><p>where MV is the full price, PMT is the coupon, FV is principal, y is yield per period and the bond settles t days into the T day period with N periods to maturity. It can be expanded as:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">dMV = (\frac{\partial MV}{\partial y}\times dy)+(\frac{1}{2}\frac{\partial^2 MV}{\partial y^2}\times dy^2)</script><p>The first expression is a duration and the second term is a convexity, which are often shown divided by 100 on Bloomberg.</p><h2 id="Duration"><a href="#Duration" class="headerlink" title="Duration"></a>Duration</h2><h3 id="Macaulay-duration"><a href="#Macaulay-duration" class="headerlink" title="Macaulay duration"></a>Macaulay duration</h3><p>measures <strong>the sensitivity of the bond’s full price</strong> (including accrued interest) to changes in the <strong>bond’s yield to maturity</strong> or, more generally, to changes in <strong>benchmark interest rates</strong>. It assumes variables other than yield or benchmark rates (including time to maturity) are unchanged:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Macaulay Duration} = -\frac{\partial  \text{MV}}{\partial y}\times\frac{1+y}{MV}=-\frac{\frac{\partial  \text{MV}}{MV}}{\frac{\partial y}{1+y}}</script><p>Duration measures <strong>instantaneous (or same day) bond price changes</strong> and may be considered a<br><strong>weighted average</strong> (the share of full price corresponding to each cash flow) of the time to receipt of<br>promised cash flows. Using an annual coupon example on a coupon date, we can simplify</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\sum_{t=1}^{n}\frac{(\text{PV of CF})\times t}{PV^{full}}</script><p>Example:</p><p>For a 6% annual coupon 5 year bond with 5% yield to maturity, the price is:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{6}{(1+r)^1}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^2}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^3}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^4}+\frac{106}{(1+r)^5} = 104.329477,~ ~ r=5\%</script><div class="table-container"><table><thead><tr><th>Period</th><th>Cash Flow</th><th>Present Value</th><th>Weight</th><th>Period $\times$ Weight</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>1</td><td>6</td><td>$\frac{6}{(1+5\%)^1}=5.714$</td><td>$\frac{5.714}{104.329}=0.0548$</td><td>0.055</td></tr><tr><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>$\frac{6}{(1+5\%)^2}=5.442$</td><td>$\frac{5.442}{104.329}=0.0522$</td><td>0.104</td></tr><tr><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>$\frac{6}{(1+5\%)^3}=5.183$</td><td>$\frac{5.183}{104.329}=0.0497$</td><td>0.149</td></tr><tr><td>4</td><td>6</td><td>$\frac{6}{(1+5\%)^4}=4.936$</td><td>$\frac{4.936}{104.329}=0.0473$</td><td>0.189</td></tr><tr><td>5</td><td>106</td><td>$\frac{106}{(1+5\%)^5}=83.054$</td><td>$\frac{83.054}{104.329}=0.7961$</td><td>3.981</td></tr><tr><td></td><td></td><td>104.329</td><td><strong>Duration</strong></td><td>4.478</td></tr></tbody></table></div><h3 id="Modified-duration"><a href="#Modified-duration" class="headerlink" title="Modified duration"></a>Modified duration</h3><p>Modified duration is a minor adjustment to Macaulay duration (dividing by 1 + yield per period) and is<br>directly related to the percentage change in a bond’s market value:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Modified Duration} = -\frac{\text{Macaulay Duration}}{(1+\frac{r}{c})}</script><p>This is a linear estimate of a fixed-rate bond’s price change for a given yield to maturity change:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\%\Delta PV = -\text{Modified Duration} \times\Delta\text{Yield}</script><p>Example:</p><p>How does the bond price in the prior example (6% annual 5 yr coupon bond with a 5% yield to maturity) change if yields decline 100 bps?</p><p>Given a Macaulay Duration of 4.478, the Modified Duration is $\frac{4.478}{1.05}=4.265$. Therefore,</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">-4.265 \times (-100bps) \times \%= 4.265\%</script><p>there will be 4.2645% price appreciation.</p><p>The error:</p><p>For original bond price:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{6}{(1+r)^1}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^2}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^3}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^4}+\frac{106}{(1+r)^5} = 104.329477,~ ~ r=5\%</script><p>For the new price estimate:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">104.329477 \times (1 + 4.2645\%) = 108.77863</script><p>For the Actual new bond price:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{6}{(1+r)^1}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^2}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^3}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^4}+\frac{106}{(1+r)^5} = 108.903645,~ ~ r=4\%</script><p>There are $108.90365 - 108.77863 = -.125$ difference in price explained by the non-linearity of the price-yield relationship.</p><h3 id="Effective-Duration"><a href="#Effective-Duration" class="headerlink" title="Effective Duration"></a>Effective Duration</h3><p>Effective Duration is <strong>the sensitivity of a bond’s price</strong> to <strong>a change in a benchmark yield curve</strong> such as a <strong>government par curve</strong>, similar to approximate modified duration except it involves a benchmark and also may be used for more complex bonds or portfolios of complex bonds</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Effective Duration} = \frac{PV_{-}-PV_{+}}{2\times(\Delta\text{Curve})(PV_0)}</script><h3 id="Money-Duration-Dollar-Duration"><a href="#Money-Duration-Dollar-Duration" class="headerlink" title="Money Duration (Dollar Duration)"></a>Money Duration (Dollar Duration)</h3><p>Dollar Duration is <strong>the price change</strong> for a given change in yield in units of the currency in which the bond is denominated (as opposed to a percentage change) stated per 100 of par or based upon an actual<br>portfolio position (known as “dollar duration in the U.S.)</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Dollar Duration} = -\frac{\part MV}{\part y}=\text{Modified Duration}\times MV</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\Delta PV = -\text{Dollar Duration} \times\Delta\text{Yield}</script><p>A related statistic is the present value of a basis point:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{PV of a Basis Point} = \frac{PV_{-} - PV_{+}}{2}</script><p>This is the dollar value (DV01) or present value of a basis point (PV01), which is calculated by increasing and decreasing the yield by 1 bp to get the price change.</p><h3 id="Portfolio-Duration"><a href="#Portfolio-Duration" class="headerlink" title="Portfolio Duration"></a>Portfolio Duration</h3><p>Portfolio duration is <strong>the sum of market value weighted durations</strong> of component positions.</p><ul><li>Positive is a long position and negative is a short position </li><li>Practitioners use duration and DV 01 PVBP statistics to analyze cash and synthetic positions to gauge net exposure, profitability and/or evaluate trade ideas</li></ul><p>Example:</p><p>A bond trader holds two 2 year U.S. Treasury notes and one 30 year U S Treasury bond. Each bond has a face value of $1000000 with 2 year duration of 1.94 and the 30 year duration of 19.69.</p><ul><li><p>Portfolio duration is $7.86 = \frac{2}{3} \times 1.94 + \frac{1}{3} \times 19.69$</p></li><li><p>Portfolio DV01 equals $7.86 \times \frac{\$3000000}{10 000} = \$2358$</p></li><li><p>If 2 year and 30 year yields rise 10 bps, her portfolio LOSS $\$23580 = \$2358 \times 10 bps$</p></li></ul><p>Coupon: For zero-coupon bonds, duration = maturity. As  Coupons increase, duration decrease.</p><p>Maturity: increase as maturity increase.</p><p>Time: As maturity decrease to 0, time goes down</p><p>Yield: As yields increase, duration decrease.</p><h2 id="Convexity"><a href="#Convexity" class="headerlink" title="Convexity"></a>Convexity</h2><p>While modified duration is a linear approximation of price changes for a given change in yield, the true price/yield relationship is a convexity adjusted equation expressed as follows:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\%\Delta PV = -\text{Modified Duration} \times\Delta\text{Yield} + \frac{1}{2}\times\text{Convexity}\times(\Delta Yield)^2</script><p>The second convexity term is positive for traditional (option free) fixed rate bond for a yield increase or decrease. Convexity may be calculated with tables, precisely derived or closely approximated:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{Convexity} = \frac{PV_-+PV_+}{(\Delta \text{yield})^2\times PV_0}</script><p>Example:</p><p>Calculate the change in full bond price from the prior example (6% annual 5 yr coupon bond with a 5% yield to maturity) given a 100 bp yield decline with the convexity adjustment?</p><p>At a yield of $5\%$, the bond price was $104.329477$ and the Modified Duration is $4.264525$, so</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\%\Delta \text{PV}=-4.264525 \times\Delta\text{Yield} = 4.2645\%</script><p>The approximate convexity with the bond price at 4.99%, 5.00%, 5.01% ($\Delta \text{Yeild}=0.0001$) as follows:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{6}{(1+r)^1}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^2}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^3}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^4}+\frac{106}{(1+r)^5} = 104.3739805,~ ~ r=4.99\%</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{6}{(1+r)^1}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^2}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^3}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^4}+\frac{106}{(1+r)^5} = 104.3294767,~ ~ r=5\%</script><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\frac{6}{(1+r)^1}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^2}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^3}+\frac{6}{(1+r)^4}+\frac{106}{(1+r)^5} = 104.2849973,~ ~ r=5.01\%</script><p>According to the formula:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\text{ApproxCon} &=& \frac{\text{PV}_{-}+\text{PV}_{+}-2\text{PV}_{0}}{(\Delta \text{Yield})^2 \times \text{PV}_{0}} \\&=&\frac{104.3739805 + 104.2849973 -2\times104.3294767}{0.0001^2\times104.3294767} \\&=& 23.444\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>Therefore, the full price change percent is:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\%\Delta\text{PV} &\approx& -4.264525 \times 0.01 + \frac{1}{2}\times23.444\times0.01^2 \\&\approx& 0.043817455\end{eqnarray*}</script><p>the convexity-adjusted price increase given -1% in yield is $4.3817455\%$, which is a $0.0026%$ difference compared to the actual price increase.</p><h2 id="Bond-Portfolio-Risk"><a href="#Bond-Portfolio-Risk" class="headerlink" title="Bond Portfolio Risk"></a>Bond Portfolio Risk</h2><h3 id="Bond-Portfolio-Duration-and-Convexity"><a href="#Bond-Portfolio-Duration-and-Convexity" class="headerlink" title="Bond Portfolio Duration and Convexity"></a>Bond Portfolio Duration and Convexity</h3><p><strong>Duration is the primary measure of price risk</strong> arising from a change in the yield to maturity. </p><ul><li>It is most important over short time horizons where investor focus is on price as opposed to coupon reinvestment risk.</li><li>Duration is also referred to as <strong>repricing risk</strong>, and it is important to note that variable rate instruments with longer maturities have short duration dictated by the timing of that repricing (such as 3 month LIBOR)</li></ul><p><strong>Convexity represents a secondary measure of price risk Investors may benefit from positive convexity</strong>, for example, a 100 year or century bond will exhibit much higher convexity than a 30 year bond despite similar duration, resulting in a larger gain amid declining interest rates.</p><p>Callable bond investors expect to be compensated for the uncertainty related to final maturity which these bonds exhibit in terms of negative convexity (i e bond price appreciation amid falling rates is effectively capped by the call feature)</p><h3 id="Portfolio-Duration-and-Convexity"><a href="#Portfolio-Duration-and-Convexity" class="headerlink" title="Portfolio Duration and Convexity"></a>Portfolio Duration and Convexity</h3><p><strong>Duration for a fixed income bond portfolio</strong> may be calculated in two ways:</p><ul><li>Weight the average time to receipt of the aggregate cash flows (which is theoretically correct but difficult to put into practice)</li><li>Weight the average of individual bond durations within the portfolio</li></ul><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\text{MV}=\frac{CF_1}{(1+\text{Yield of Portfolio})^1}+\frac{CF_2}{(1+\text{Yield of Portfolio})^2}+...+\frac{CF_N}{(1+\text{Yield of Portfolio})^N}</script><p>Theoretically, the formula above should be based upon a homogenous non-callable bond portfolio where the full and flat price are equal, but in practice, the weighted averages are used:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{eqnarray*}\text{AvgMacDur of Portfolio} &=& \sum_{j=1}^{J}\text{MacDur}_j\times\left(\frac{\text{MV}_{j}}{\text{MV}}\right) \\\text{AvgModDur of Portfolio} &=& \sum_{j=1}^{J}\text{ModDur}_j\times\left(\frac{\text{MV}_{j}}{\text{MV}}\right) \\\text{AvgConvexity of Portfolio} &=& \sum_{j=1}^{J}\text{Convexity}_j\times\left(\frac{\text{MV}_{j}}{\text{MV}}\right)\end{eqnarray*}</script><h3 id="Source-of-Bond-YTM-Changes"><a href="#Source-of-Bond-YTM-Changes" class="headerlink" title="Source of Bond YTM Changes"></a>Source of Bond YTM Changes</h3><p>Yield changes may originate in either benchmark or spread changes or a combination of the two<br>components.</p><p><strong>Credit spread example</strong>:</p><p>A risk manager is tasked with weighing the relative risk of two spread positions under a recession scenario<br>Bond 1 has modified duration of 3.00 and a convexity of 24.00 and is expected to face 25 bps of spread<br>widening, and Bond 2 has modified duration of 5.00 and a convexity of 40.00 and is expected to see<br>spreads widen by 15 bps in a downturn. Which bond has more price risk? Bond 2 has slightly more risk:</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\% \Delta \text{PV}_\text{Full} \approx (-3\times0.0025) + \left[\frac{1}{2}\times24\times(0.0025)^2\right] \approx-0.007425 \\\% \Delta \text{PV}_\text{Full} \approx (-5\times0.0015) + \left[\frac{1}{2}\times40\times(0.0015)^2\right] \approx-0.007455</script><p><strong>Liquidity example:</strong></p><p>A trader’s boss wants her to gauge the precise bid offer cost of liquidating a thinly traded corporate bond<br>position The face value is $\$120 000 000$ with a modified duration of 4.5 and convexity of 35 and the bid<br>offer cost is expected to be 5 bps What is the estimated cost of trading the position?</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">\%\Delta\text{PV} \approx -4.5 \times 0.0005 + \frac{1}{2}\times35\times0.0005^2 \approx -0.002245625</script><p>That means the estimated trading cost using modified duration only is</p><script type="math/tex; mode=display">$120000000\times-0.0022445625 = -$269475</script><h1 id="Other-Products"><a href="#Other-Products" class="headerlink" title="Other Products"></a>Other Products</h1><h2 id="Risk-free-rate-Repurchase-agreement"><a href="#Risk-free-rate-Repurchase-agreement" class="headerlink" title="Risk free rate: Repurchase agreement"></a>Risk free rate: Repurchase agreement</h2><h2 id="Interest-Rate-Swap"><a href="#Interest-Rate-Swap" class="headerlink" title="Interest Rate Swap"></a>Interest Rate Swap</h2>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;This notes is based on the class Financial Risk Management of NYU MFE, including basic conceptions of Fixed Income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Fixed-Inc
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Economics" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/"/>
    
      <category term="Finance" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/"/>
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/Economics/Finance/Risk-Management/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Risk Management" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/Risk-Management/"/>
    
      <category term="NYU" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/NYU/"/>
    
      <category term="FRM" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/FRM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
